CHAPTER ONE
THE BOY WHO LIVED
Mr. and Mrs. Dursley,
of number four,
Privet Drive,
were proud to say that they were perfectly normal,
thank you very much.
They were the last people you'd expect to be
involved in anything strange or mysterious,
because they just didn't hold with such nonsense.
Mr. Dursley was the director
of a firm called Grunnings,
which made drills.
He was a big,
beefy man with hardly any neck,
although he did have a very large mustache.
Mrs. Dursley was thin and blonde and had
nearly twice the usual amount of neck,
which came in very useful as she spent so
much of her time craning over garden fences,
spying on the neighbors.
The Dursleys had a small son called Dudley
and in their opinion there
was no finer boy anywhere.
The Dursleys had everything they wanted,
but they also had a secret,
and their greatest fear was
that somebody would discover it.
They didn't think they could bear it
if anyone found out about the Potters.
Mrs. Potter was Mrs. Dursley's sister,
but they hadn't met for several years;
in fact, Mrs. Dursley pretended
she didn't have a sister,
because her sister and her
good-for-nothing husband
were as unDursleyish as it was possible to be.
The Dursleys shuddered to think
what the neighbors would say if
the Potters arrived in the street.
The Dursleys knew that the
Potters had a small son,
too, but they had never even seen him.
This boy was another good reason
for keeping the Potters away;
they didn't want Dudley
mixing with a child like that.
When Mr. and Mrs. Dursley woke up on the dull,
gray Tuesday our story starts,
there was nothing about the cloudy
sky outside to suggest that strange
and mysterious things would soon
be happening all over the country.
Mr. Dursley hummed as he picked
out his most boring tie for work,
and Mrs. Dursley gossiped away happily as she
wrestled a screaming Dudley into his high chair.
None of them noticed a large,
tawny owl flutter past the window.
At half past eight,
Mr. Dursley picked up his briefcase,
pecked Mrs. Dursley on the cheek,
and tried to kiss Dudley good-bye but missed,
because Dudley was now having a tantrum
and throwing his cereal at the walls.
"Little tyke,"
chortled Mr. Dursley as he left the house.
He got into his car and backed
out of number four's drive.
It was on the corner of the street that he
noticed the first sign of something peculiar ,
a cat reading a map.
For a second,
Mr. Dursley didn't realize what he had seen ,
then he jerked his head around to look again.
There was a tabby cat standing
on the corner of Privet Drive,
but there wasn't a map in sight.
What could he have been thinking of?
It must have been a trick of the light.
Mr. Dursley blinked and stared at the cat.
It stared back.
As Mr. Dursley drove around
the corner and up the road,
he watched the cat in his mirror.
It was now reading the sign
that said Privet Drive ,
no, looking at the sign;
cats couldn't read maps or signs.
Mr. Dursley gave himself a little
shake and put the cat out of his mind.
As he drove toward town he thought of nothing
except a large order of drills he was hoping
to get that day.
But on the edge of town,
drills were driven out of
his mind by something else.
As he sat in the usual morning traffic jam,
he couldn't help noticing that there seemed
to be a lot of strangely dressed people about.
People in cloaks.
Mr. Dursley couldn't bear people
who dressed in funny clothes ,
the getups you saw on young people!
He supposed this was some stupid new fashion.
He drummed his fingers on the steering wheel
and his eyes fell on a huddle of
these weirdos standing quite close by.
They were whispering excitedly together.
Mr. Dursley was enraged to see that a
couple of them weren't young at all;
why, that man had to be older than he was,
and wearing an emerald-green cloak!
The nerve of him!
But then it struck Mr. Dursley that
this was probably some silly stunt ,
these people were obviously
collecting for something...
yes, that would be it.
The traffic moved on and a few minutes later,
Mr. Dursley arrived in the Grunnings parking lot,
his mind back on drills.
Mr. Dursley always sat with his back to the
window in his office on the ninth floor.
If he hadn't,
he might have found it harder to
concentrate on drills that morning.
He didn't see the owls swoop
ing past in broad daylight,
though people down in the street did;
they pointed and gazed open- mouthed
as owl after owl sped overhead.
Most of them had never seen
an owl even at nighttime.
Mr. Dursley,
however, had a perfectly normal,
owl-free morning.
He yelled at five different people.
He made several important telephone
calls and shouted a bit more.
He was in a very good mood until lunchtime,
when he thought he'd stretch his legs
and walk across the road to buy
himself a bun from the bakery.
He'd forgotten all about the people
in cloaks until he passed a group
of them next to the baker's.
He eyed them angrily as he passed.
He didn't know why,
but they made him uneasy.
This bunch were whispering excitedly,
too, and he couldn't see a single collecting tin.
It was on his way back past them,
clutching a large doughnut in a bag,
that he caught a few words
of what they were saying.
"The Potters,
that's right,
that's what I heard yes,
their son, Harry"
Mr. Dursley stopped dead.
Fear flooded him.
He looked back at the whisperers as
if he wanted to say something to them,
but thought better of it.
He dashed back across the road,
hurried up to his office,
snapped at his secretary not to disturb him,
seized his telephone,
and had almost finished dialing his
home number when he changed his mind.
He put the receiver back down
and stroked his mustache,
thinking...
no, he was being stupid.
Potter wasn't such an unusual name.
He was sure there were lots of people
called Potter who had a son called Harry.
Come to think of it,
he wasn't even sure his nephew was called Harry.
He'd never even seen the boy.
It might have been Harvey. Or Harold.
There was no point in worrying Mrs. Dursley;
she always got so upset at
any mention of her sister.
He didn't blame her ,
if he'd had a sister like that...
but all the same,
those people in cloaks...
He found it a lot harder to concentrate
on drills that afternoon and
when he left the building at five o'clock,
he was still so worried that he walked
straight into someone just outside the door.
"Sorry,"
he grunted,
as the tiny old man stumbled and almost fell.
It was a few seconds before Mr. Dursley realized
that the man was wearing a violet cloak.
He didn't seem at all upset at
being almost knocked to the ground.
On the contrary,
his face split into a wide smile and he said
in a squeaky voice that made passersby stare,
"Don't be sorry,
my dear sir,
for nothing could upset me today!
Rejoice, for You-Know-Who has gone at last!
Even Muggles like yourself should be celebrating,
this happy,
happy day!"
And the old man hugged Mr. Dursley
around the middle and walked off.
Mr. Dursley stood rooted to the spot.
He had been hugged by a complete stranger.
He also thought he had been called a Muggle,
whatever that was.
He was rattled.
He hurried to his car and set off for home,
hoping he was imagining things,
which he had never hoped before,
because he didn't approve of imagination.
As he pulled into the driveway of number four,
the first thing he saw ,
and it didn't improve his mood ,
was the tabby cat he'd spotted that morning.
It was now sitting on his garden wall.
He was sure it was the same one;
it had the same markings around its eyes.
"Shoo!"
said Mr. Dursley loudly.
The cat didn't move.
It just gave him a stern look.
Was this normal cat behavior?
Mr. Dursley wondered.
Trying to pull himself together,
he let himself into the house.
He was still determined not to
mention anything to his wife.
Mrs. Dursley had had a nice,
normal day.
She told him over dinner all about Mrs.
Next Door's problems with her daughter and
how Dudley had learned a new word (
"Won't!" ).
Mr. Dursley tried to act normally.
When Dudley had been put to bed,
he went into the living room in time to
catch the last report on the evening news:
"And finally,
bird-watchers everywhere have reported
that the nation's owls have been
behaving very unusually today.
Although owls normally hunt at night
and are hardly ever seen in daylight,
there have been hundreds of
sightings of these birds flying
in every direction since sunrise.
Experts are unable to explain why the owls
have suddenly changed their sleeping pattern."
The newscaster allowed himself a grin.
"Most mysterious.
And now, over to Jim McGuffin with the weather.
Going to be any more showers of owls tonight,
Jim?"
"Well, Ted,"
said the weatherman,
"I don't know about that,
but it's not only the owls that
have been acting oddly today.
Viewers as far apart as Kent,
Yorkshire, and Dundee have been phoning in to tell
me that instead of the rain I promised yesterday,
they've had a downpour of shooting stars!
Perhaps people have been
celebrating Bonfire Night early ,
it's not until next week, folks!
But I can promise a wet night tonight."
Mr. Dursley sat frozen in his armchair.
Shooting stars all over Britain?
Owls flying by daylight?
Mysterious people in cloaks all over the place?
And a whisper,
a whisper about the Potters...
Mrs. Dursley came into the living
room carrying two cups of tea.
It was no good.
He'd have to say something to her.
He cleared his throat nervously.
"Er , Petunia,
dear , you haven't heard from your sister lately,
have you?"
As he had expected,
Mrs. Dursley looked shocked and angry.
After all, they normally pretended
she didn't have a sister.
"No,"
she said sharply.
"Why?"
"Funny stuff on the news,"
Mr. Dursley mumbled. "Owls...
shooting stars...
and there were a lot of funny-looking
people in town today..."
"So?"
snapped Mrs. Dursley.
"Well, I just thought... maybe...
it was something to do with...
you know...
her crowd."
Mrs. Dursley sipped her tea through pursed lips.
Mr. Dursley wondered whether he
dared tell her he'd heard the name
"Potter."
He decided he didn't dare. Instead
he said, as casually as he could,
"Their son , he'd be about
Dudley's age now, wouldn't he?"
"I suppose so,"
said Mrs. Dursley stiffly.
"What's his name again? Howard, isn't it?"
"Harry. Nasty, common name, if you ask me."
"Oh, yes,"
said Mr. Dursley, his heart sinking horribly.
"Yes, I quite agree."
He didn't say another word on the
subject as they went upstairs to bed.
While Mrs. Dursley was in the bathroom,
Mr. Dursley crept to the bedroom window
and peered down into the front garden.
The cat was still there.
It was staring down Privet Drive as
though it were waiting for something.
Was he imagining things?
Could all this have anything
to do with the Potters?
If it did...
if it got out that they
were related to a pair of ,
well, he didn't think he could bear it.
The Dursleys got into bed.
Mrs. Dursley fell asleep quickly
but Mr. Dursley lay awake,
turning it all over in his mind.
His last, comforting thought before he fell
asleep was that even if the Potters were involved,
there was no reason for them to
come near him and Mrs. Dursley.
The Potters knew very well what he and
Petunia thought about them and their kind....
He couldn't see how he and Petunia could get
mixed up in anything that might be going on ,
he yawned and turned over ,
it couldn't affect them....
How very wrong he was.
Mr. Dursley might have been
drifting into an uneasy sleep,
but the cat on the wall outside
was showing no sign of sleepiness.
It was sitting as still as a statue,
its eyes fixed unblinkingly on
the far corner of Privet Drive.
It didn't so much as quiver when a
car door slammed on the next street,
nor when two owls swooped overhead.
In fact, it was nearly midnight
before the cat moved at all.
A man appeared on the corner
the cat had been watching,
appeared so suddenly and silently you'd have
thought he'd just popped out of the ground.
The cat's tail twitched and its eyes narrowed.
Nothing like this man had ever
been seen on Privet Drive.
He was tall,
thin, and very old,
judging by the silver of his hair and beard,
which were both long enough to tuck into his belt.
He was wearing long robes,
a purple cloak that swept the ground,
and high-heeled,
buckled boots.
His blue eyes were light,
bright, and sparkling behind half-moon spectacles
and his nose was very long and crooked,
as though it had been broken at least twice.
This man's name was Albus Dumbledore.
Albus Dumbledore didn't seem to realize
that he had just arrived in a street
where everything from his name
to his boots was unwelcome.
He was busy rummaging in his cloak,
looking for something.
But he did seem to realize he was being watched,
because he looked up suddenly at the cat,
which was still staring at him
from the other end of the street.
For some reason,
the sight of the cat seemed to amuse him.
He chuckled and muttered,
"I should have known."
He found what he was looking
for in his inside pocket.
It seemed to be a silver cigarette lighter.
He flicked it open,
held it up in the air,
and clicked it.
The nearest street lamp
went out with a little pop.
He clicked it again ,
the next lamp flickered into darkness.
Twelve times he clicked the Put-Outer,
until the only lights left on the whole street
were two tiny pinpricks in the distance,
which were the eyes of the cat watching him.
If anyone looked out of their window now,
even beady-eyed Mrs. Dursley,
they wouldn't be able to see anything
that was happening down on the pavement.
Dumbledore slipped the
Put-Outer back inside his cloak
and set off down the street toward number four,
where he sat down on the wall next to the cat.
He didn't look at it,
but after a moment he spoke to it.
"Fancy seeing you here, Professor McGonagall."
He turned to smile at the tabby,
but it had gone.
Instead he was smiling at a
rather severe-looking woman
who was wearing square glasses exactly the shape
of the markings the cat had had around its eyes.
She, too, was wearing a cloak,
an emerald one.
Her black hair was drawn into a tight bun.
She looked distinctly ruffled.
"How did you know it was me?" she asked.
"My dear Professor, I 've never
seen a cat sit so stiffly."
"You'd be stiff if you'd been
sitting on a brick wall all day,"
said Professor McGonagall. "All day?
When you could have been celebrating?
I must have passed a dozen feasts
and parties on my way here."
Professor McGonagall sniffed angrily.
"Oh yes, everyone's celebrating, all right,"
she said impatiently.
"You'd think they'd be a bit more careful,
but no , even the Muggles have
noticed something's going on.
It was on their news."
She jerked her head back at the
Dursleys' dark living-room window.
"I heard it.
Flocks of owls...
shooting stars....
Well, they're not completely stupid.
They were bound to notice something.
Shooting stars down in Kent ,
I'll bet that was Dedalus Diggle.
He never had much sense."
"You can't blame them,"
said Dumbledore gently.
"We've had precious little to
celebrate for eleven years."
"I know that,"
said Professor McGonagall irritably.
"But that's no reason to lose our heads.
People are being downright careless,
out on the streets in broad daylight,
not even dressed in Muggle clothes,
swapping rumors."
She threw a sharp,
sideways glance at Dumbledore here,
as though hoping he was
going to tell her something,
but he didn't,
so she went on.
"A fine thing it would be if,
on the very day YouKnow-Who seems
to have disappeared at last,
the Muggles found out about us all.
I suppose he really has gone,
Dumbledore?"
"It certainly seems so,"
said Dumbledore.
"We have much to be thankful for.
Would you care for a lemon drop?"
"A what?"
"A lemon drop. They're a kind of
Muggle sweet I'm rather fond of"
"No, thank you,"
said Professor McGonagall coldly,
as though she didn't think this
was the moment for lemon drops.
"As I say, even if You-Know-Who has gone -"
"My dear Professor,
surely a sensible person like
yourself can call him by his name?
All this 'You- Know-Who' nonsense ,
for eleven years I have been trying
to persuade people to call him
by his proper name: Voldemort."
Professor McGonagall flinched,
but Dumbledore,
who was unsticking two lemon drops,
seemed not to notice.
"It all gets so confusing
if we keep saying 'You-Know-Who.'
I have never seen any reason to be
frightened of saying Voldemort's name.
"I know you haven 't,
said Professor McGonagall,
sounding half exasperated,
half admiring.
"
But you're different.
Everyone knows you're the only one You-Know- oh,
all right, Voldemort,
was frightened of."
"You flatter me,"
said Dumbledore calmly.
"Voldemort had powers I will never have."
"Only because you're too ,
well , noble to use them."
"It's lucky it's dark.
I haven't blushed so much since Madam
Pomfrey told me she liked my new earmuffs."
Professor McGonagall shot a sharp
look at Dumbledore and said,
"The owls are nothing next to the
rumors that are flying around.
You know what everyone's saying?
About why he's disappeared?
About what finally stopped him?"
It seemed that Professor McGonagall had reached
the point she was most anxious to discuss,
the real reason she had been waiting on a cold,
hard wall all day,
for neither as a cat nor as a
woman had she fixed Dumbledore
with such a piercing stare as she did now.
It was plain that whatever
"everyone"
was saying,
she was not going to believe it until
Dumbledore told her it was true.
Dumbledore,
however, was choosing another
lemon drop and did not answer.
"What they're saying,"
she pressed on,
"is that last night Voldemort
turned up in Godric's Hollow.
He went to find the Potters.
The rumor is that Lily and James Potter are ,
are , that they're , dead.
"
Dumbledore bowed his head.
Professor McGonagall gasped.
"Lily and James...
I can't believe it...
I didn't want to believe it...
Oh, Albus..."
Dumbledore reached out and
patted her on the shoulder.
"I know... I know..."
he said heavily.
Professor McGonagall's voice
trembled as she went on.
"That's not all.
They're saying he tried to
kill the Potter's son, Harry.
But , he couldn't.
He couldn't kill that little boy.
No one knows why,
or how, but they're saying that
when he couldn't kill Harry Potter,
Voldemort's power somehow broke ,
and that's why he's gone.
Dumbledore nodded glumly.
"It's , it's true?"
faltered Professor McGonagall.
"After all he's done...
all the people he's killed...
he couldn't kill a little boy?
It's just astounding...
of all the things to stop him...
but how in the name of heaven did Harry survive?"
"We can only guess,"
said Dumbledore.
"We may never know."
Professor McGonagall pulled
out a lace handkerchief
and dabbed at her eyes beneath her spectacles.
Dumbledore gave a great sniff as he took a
golden watch from his pocket and examined it.
It was a very odd watch.
It had twelve hands but no numbers;
instead, little planets
were moving around the edge.
It must have made sense to Dumbledore,
though, because he put it
back in his pocket and said,
"Hagrid's late.
I suppose it was he who told you I'd be here,
by the way?"
"Yes,"
said Professor McGonagall.
"And I don't suppose you're
going to tell me why you're here,
of all places?"
"I've come to bring Harry to his aunt and uncle.
They're the only family he has left now."
"You don't mean , you can't
mean the people who live here?"
cried Professor McGonagall,
jumping to her feet and pointing at number four.
"Dumbledore , you can't.
I've been watching them all day.
You couldn't find two people who are less like us.
And they've got this son ,
I saw him kicking his mother
all the way up the street,
screaming for sweets.
Harry Potter come and live here!"
"It's the best place for him,"
said Dumbledore firmly.
"His aunt and uncle will be able to
explain everything to him when he's older.
I've written them a letter."
"A letter?"
repeated Professor McGonagall faintly,
sitting back down on the wall.
"Really, Dumbledore,
you think you can explain all this in a letter?
These people will never understand him!
He'll be famous ,
a legend , I wouldn't be surprised if today
was known as Harry Potter day in the future ,
there will be books written about Harry ,
every child in our world will know his name!"
"Exactly,"
said Dumbledore,
looking very seriously over the
top of his half-moon glasses.
"It would be enough to turn any boy's head.
Famous before he can walk and talk!
Famous for something he won't even remember!
CarA you see how much better off he'll be,
growing up away from all that
until he's ready to take it?"
Professor McGonagall opened her mouth,
changed her mind,
swallowed, and then said,
"Yes , yes,
you're right, of course.
But how is the boy getting here,
Dumbledore?"
She eyed his cloak suddenly as though she
thought he might be hiding Harry underneath it.
"Hagrid's bringing him."
"You think it ,
wise , to trust Hagrid with
something as important as this?"
I would trust Hagrid with
my life," said Dumbledore.
"I'm not saying his heart
isn't in the right place,"
said Professor McGonagall grudgingly,
"but you can't pretend he's not careless.
He does tend to ,
what was that?"
A low rumbling sound had
broken the silence around them.
It grew steadily louder as they looked up
and down the street for some sign of a headlight;
it swelled to a roar as they
both looked up at the sky ,
and a huge motorcycle fell out of the air
and landed on the road in front of them.
If the motorcycle was huge,
it was nothing to the man sitting astride it.
He was almost twice as tall as a normal
man and at least five times as wide.
He looked simply too big to be allowed,
and so wild - long tangles of bushy black
hair and beard hid most of his face,
he had hands the size of trash can lids,
and his feet in their leather
boots were like baby dolphins.
In his vast,
muscular arms he was holding a bundle of blankets.
"Hagrid,"
said Dumbledore, sounding relieved.
"At last. And where did you get that motorcycle?"
"Borrowed it, Professor Dumbledore, sit,"
said the giant, climbing carefully
off the motorcycle as he spoke.
"Young Sirius Black lent it
to me. I've got him, sir."
"No problems, were there?"
"No, sir , house was almost destroyed,
but I got him out all right before
the Muggles started swarmin' around.
He fell asleep as we was flyin' over Bristol."
Dumbledore and Professor McGonagall bent
forward over the bundle of blankets.
Inside, just visible,
was a baby boy,
fast asleep.
Under a tuft of jet-black hair over his
forehead they could see a curiously shaped cut,
like a bolt of lightning.
"Is that where -?"
whispered Professor McGonagall.
"Yes,"
said Dumbledore.
"He'll have that scar forever."
"Couldn't you do something about it, Dumbledore?"
"Even if I could,
I wouldn't.
Scars can come in handy.
I have one myself above my left knee that
is a perfect map of the London Underground.
Well , give him here,
Hagrid , we'd better get this over with."
Dumbledore took Harry in his arms and
turned toward the Dursleys' house.
"Could I , could I say good-bye to him, sir?"
asked Hagrid.
He bent his great,
shaggy head over Harry and gave him
what must have been a very scratchy,
whiskery kiss.
Then, suddenly,
Hagrid let out a howl like a wounded dog.
"Shhh!"
hissed Professor McGonagall,
"you'll wake the Muggles!"
"S-s-sorry,"
sobbed Hagrid,
taking out a large,
spotted handkerchief and burying his face in it.
"But I c-c-can't stand it ,
Lily an' James dead ,
an' poor little Harry off ter live with Muggles -"
"Yes, yes, it's all very sad,
but get a grip on yourself,
Hagrid, or we'll be found,"
Professor McGonagall whispered,
patting Hagrid gingerly on the arm as
Dumbledore stepped over the low garden wall
and walked to the front door.
He laid Harry gently on the doorstep,
took a letter out of his cloak,
tucked it inside Harry's blankets,
and then came back to the other two.
For a full minute the three of them
stood and looked at the little bundle;
Hagrid's shoulders shook,
Professor McGonagall blinked furiously,
and the twinkling light that usually shone
from Dumbledore's eyes seemed to have gone out.
"Well,"
said Dumbledore finally,
"that's that.
We've no business staying here.
We may as well go and join the celebrations."
"Yeah,"
said Hagrid in a very muffled voice,
"I'll be takin' Sirius his bike back.
G'night, Professor McGonagall ,
Professor Dumbledore,
sir."
Wiping his streaming eyes on his jacket sleeve,
Hagrid swung himself onto the motorcycle
and kicked the engine into life;
with a roar it rose into the
air and off into the night.
"I shall see you soon, I
expect, Professor McGonagall,"
said Dumbledore,
nodding to her.
Professor McGonagall blew her nose in reply.
Dumbledore turned and walked back down the street.
On the corner he stopped and
took out the silver Put-Outer.
He clicked it once,
and twelve balls of light sped
back to their street lamps so
that Privet Drive glowed suddenly orange
and he could make out a tabby
cat slinking around the corner
at the other end of the street.
He could just see the bundle of
blankets on the step of number four.
"Good luck, Harry,"
he murmured.
He turned on his heel and
with a swish of his cloak,
he was gone.
A breeze ruffled the neat hedges of Privet Drive,
which lay silent and tidy under the inky sky,
the very last place you would
expect astonishing things to happen.
Harry Potter rolled over inside
his blankets without waking up.
One small hand closed on the
letter beside him and he slept on,
not knowing he was special,
not knowing he was famous,
not knowing he would be woken
in a few hours' time by Mrs. Dursley's
scream as she opened the front door
to put out the milk bottles,
nor that he would spend the
next few weeks being prodded
and pinched by his cousin Dudley...
He couldn't know that at this very moment,
people meeting in secret all over the
country were holding up their glasses
and saying in hushed voices:
"To Harry Potter , the boy who lived!"
CHAPTER TWO
THE VANISHING GLASS
Nearly ten years had passed since the
Dursleys had woken up to find their nephew
on the front step,
but Privet Drive had hardly changed at all.
The sun rose on the same tidy front gardens
and lit up the brass number four
on the Dursleys' front door;
it crept into their living room,
which was almost exactly the
same as it had been on the night
when Mr. Dursley had seen that
fateful news report about the owls.
Only the photographs on the mantelpiece
really showed how much time had passed.
Ten years ago,
there had been lots of pictures of
what looked like a large pink beach
ball wearing different-colored bonnets ,
but Dudley Dursley was no longer a baby,
and now the photographs showed a large
blond boy riding his first bicycle,
on a carousel at the fair,
playing a computer game with his father,
being hugged and kissed by his mother.
The room held no sign at all that
another boy lived in the house, too.
Yet Harry Potter was still there,
asleep at the moment,
but not for long.
His Aunt Petunia was awake
and it was her shrill voice that
made the first noise of the day.
"Up! Get up! Now!"
Harry woke with a start. His
aunt rapped on the door again.
"Up!"
she screeched.
Harry heard her walking toward the kitchen
and then the sound of the frying
pan being put on the stove.
He rolled onto his back and tried to
remember the dream he had been having.
It had been a good one.
There had been a flying motorcycle in it.
He had a funny feeling he'd
had the same dream before.
His aunt was back outside the door.
"Are you up yet?"
she demanded.
"Nearly,"
said Harry.
"Well, get a move on,
I want you to look after the bacon.
And don't you dare let it burn,
I want everything perfect on Duddy's birthday."
Harry groaned.
"What did you say?"
his aunt snapped through the door.
"Nothing, nothing..."
Dudley's birthday ,
how could he have forgotten?
Harry got slowly out of bed
and started looking for socks.
He found a pair under his bed and,
after pulling a spider off one of them,
put them on.
Harry was used to spiders,
because the cupboard under
the stairs was full of them,
and that was where he slept.
When he was dressed he went
down the hall into the kitchen.
The table was almost hidden beneath
all Dudley's birthday presents.
It looked as though Dudley had
gotten the new computer he wanted,
not to mention the second
television and the racing bike.
Exactly why Dudley wanted a racing
bike was a mystery to Harry,
as Dudley was very fat and hated exercise ,
unless of course it involved punching somebody.
Dudley's favorite punching bag was Harry,
but he couldn't often catch him.
Harry didn't look it,
but he was very fast.
Perhaps it had something to do
with living in a dark cupboard,
but Harry had always been
small and skinny for his age.
He looked even smaller and
skinnier than he really was
because all he had to wear
were old clothes of Dudley's,
and Dudley was about four
times bigger than he was.
Harry had a thin face,
knobbly knees,
black hair,
and bright green eyes.
He wore round glasses held
together with a lot of Scotch tape
because of all the times Dudley
had punched him on the nose.
The only thing Harry liked about his
own appearance was a very thin scar
on his forehead that was shaped
like a bolt of lightning.
He had had it as long as he could remember,
and the first question he could ever
remember asking his Aunt Petunia was
how he had gotten it.
"In the car crash when your parents died,"
she had said.
"And don't ask questions."
Don't ask questions ,
that was the first rule for a
quiet life with the Dursleys.
Uncle Vernon entered the kitchen as
Harry was turning over the bacon.
"Comb your hair!"
he barked, by way of a morning greeting.
About once a week,
Uncle Vernon looked over the top of his newspaper
and shouted that Harry needed a haircut.
Harry must have had more haircuts than
the rest of the boys in his class put
together, but it made no difference,
his hair simply grew that way ,
all over the place.
Harry was frying eggs by the time Dudley
arrived in the kitchen with his mother.
Dudley looked a lot like Uncle Vernon.
He had a large pink face,
not much neck,
small, watery blue eyes,
and thick blond hair that lay
smoothly on his thick, fat head.
Aunt Petunia often said that
Dudley looked like a baby angel ,
Harry often said that Dudley
looked like a pig in a wig.
Harry put the plates of
egg and bacon on the table,
which was difficult as there wasn't much room.
Dudley, meanwhile,
was counting his presents.
His face fell.
"Thirty-six,"
he said, looking up at his mother and father.
"That's two less than last year."
"Darling, you haven't counted
Auntie Marge's present,
see, it's here under this big
one from Mommy and Daddy."
"All right, thirty-seven then,"
said Dudley,
going red in the face.
Harry, who could see a huge
Dudley tantrum coming on,
began wolfing down his bacon as fast as
possible in case Dudley turned the table over.
Aunt Petunia obviously scented danger,
too, because she said quickly,
"And we'll buy you another two
presents while we're out today.
How's that, popkin?
Two more presents.
Is that all right''
Dudley thought for a moment.
It looked like hard work.
Finally he said slowly,
"So I'll have thirty ... thirty..."
"Thirty-nine, sweetums,"
said Aunt Petunia.
"Oh."
Dudley sat down heavily and
grabbed the nearest parcel.
"All right then."
Uncle Vernon chuckled.
"Little tyke wants his money's worth,
just like his father.
'Atta boy, Dudley!"
He ruffled Dudley's hair.
At that moment the telephone rang
and Aunt Petunia went to answer it while Harry
and Uncle Vernon watched
Dudley unwrap the racing bike,
a video camera,
a remote control airplane,
sixteen new computer games, and a VCR.
He was ripping the paper off a gold wristwatch
when Aunt Petunia came back from the
telephone looking both angry and worried.
"Bad news, Vernon," she said.
"Mrs. Figg's broken her leg. She can't take him."
She jerked her head in Harry's direction.
Dudley's mouth fell open in horror,
but Harry's heart gave a leap.
Every year on Dudley's birthday,
his parents took him and a friend out for the day,
to adventure parks,
hamburger restaurants,
or the movies.
Every year,
Harry was left behind with Mrs. Figg,
a mad old lady who lived two streets away.
Harry hated it there.
The whole house smelled of cabbage
and Mrs. Figg made him look at photographs
of all the cats she'd ever owned.
"Now what?"
said Aunt Petunia,
looking furiously at Harry
as though he'd planned this.
Harry knew he ought to feel sorry
that Mrs. Figg had broken her leg,
but it wasn't easy when he reminded
himself it would be a whole year
before he had to look at Tibbles,
Snowy, Mr. Paws,
and Tufty again.
"We could phone Marge,"
Uncle Vernon suggested.
"Don't be silly, Vernon, she hates the boy."
The Dursleys often spoke about Harry like this,
as though he wasn't there ,
or rather, as though he was something
very nasty that couldn't understand them,
like a slug.
"What about what's-her-name,
your friend , Yvonne?"
"On vacation in Majorca,"
snapped Aunt Petunia.
"You could just leave me here,"
Harry put in hopefully (he'd be able to watch
what he wanted on television for a change and
maybe even have a go on Dudley's computer).
Aunt Petunia looked as though
she'd just swallowed a lemon.
"And come back and find the house in ruins?"
she snarled.
"I won't blow up the house,"
said Harry, but they weren't listening.
"I suppose we could take him to the zoo,"
said Aunt Petunia slowly,
"... and leave him in the car...."
"That car's new, he's not sitting in it alone...."
Dudley began to cry loudly.
In fact, he wasn't really crying ,
it had been years since he'd really cried ,
but he knew that if he screwed
up his face and wailed,
his mother would give him anything he wanted.
"Dinky Duddydums,
don't cry, Mummy won't let
him spoil your special day!"
she cried, flinging her arms around him.
"I... don't... want... him... t-t-to come!"
Dudley yelled between huge, pretend sobs.
"He always sp- spoils everything!"
He shot Harry a nasty grin through
the gap in his mother's arms.
Just then, the doorbell rang ,
"Oh, good Lord, they're here!"
said Aunt Petunia frantically ,
and a moment later,
Dudley's best friend,
Piers Polkiss,
walked in with his mother.
Piers was a scrawny boy with a face like a rat.
He was usually the one who held people's arms
behind their backs while Dudley hit them.
Dudley stopped pretending to cry at once.
Half an hour later,
Harry, who couldn't believe his luck,
was sitting in the back of the
Dursleys' car with Piers and Dudley,
on the way to the zoo for
the first time in his life.
His aunt and uncle hadn't been able to
think of anything else to do with him,
but before they'd left,
Uncle Vernon had taken Harry aside.
"I'm warning you,"
he had said, putting his large purple
face right up close to Harry's,
"I'm warning you now,
boy , any funny business,
anything at all ,
and you'll be in that cupboard
from now until Christmas."
"I'm not going to do anything,"
said Harry, "honestly..
But Uncle Vernon didn't
believe him. No one ever did.
The problem was,
strange things often happened around Harry
and it was just no good telling the
Dursleys he didn't make them happen.
Once, Aunt Petunia,
tired of Harry coming back from the barbers
looking as though he hadn't been at all,
had taken a pair of kitchen scissors
and cut his hair so short he was
almost bald except for his bangs,
which she left
"to hide that horrible scar."
Dudley had laughed himself silly at Harry,
who spent a sleepless night
imagining school the next day,
where he was already laughed at for
his baggy clothes and taped glasses.
Next morning,
however, he had gotten up to find
his hair exactly as it had been
before Aunt Petunia had sheared it off He had
been given a week in his cupboard for this,
even though he had tried to
explain that he couldn't explain
how it had grown back so quickly.
Another time,
Aunt Petunia had been trying to force him into
a revolting old sweater of Dudley's (brown
with orange puff balls) ,
The harder she tried to pull it over his head,
the smaller it seemed to become,
until finally it might have fitted a hand puppet,
but certainly wouldn't fit Harry.
Aunt Petunia had decided it must
have shrunk in the wash and,
to his great relief,
Harry wasn't punished.
On the other hand,
he'd gotten into terrible trouble for being
found on the roof of the school kitchens.
Dudley's gang had been chasing him as usual when,
as much to Harry's surprise as anyone else's,
there he was sitting on the chimney.
The Dursleys had received a very angry letter
from Harry's headmistress telling them
Harry had been climbing school buildings.
But all he'd tried to do (as he shouted
at Uncle Vernon through the locked door
of his cupboard) was jump behind the big
trash cans outside the kitchen doors.
Harry supposed that the wind must
have caught him in mid- jump.
But today, nothing was going to go wrong.
It was even worth being with Dudley
and Piers to be spending the day
somewhere that wasn't school,
his cupboard,
or Mrs. Figg's cabbage-smelling living room.
While he drove,
Uncle Vernon complained to Aunt Petunia.
He liked to complain about things: people at work,
Harry, the council,
Harry, the bank,
and Harry were just a few
of his favorite subjects.
This morning,
it was motorcycles.
"... roaring along like
maniacs, the young hoodlums,"
he said, as a motorcycle overtook them.
I had a dream about a motorcycle,
" said Harry, remembering suddenly. "
It was flying."
Uncle Vernon nearly crashed into the car in front.
He turned right around in
his seat and yelled at Harry,
his face like a gigantic beet with a mustache:
"MOTORCYCLES DON'T FLY!"
Dudley and Piers sniggered.
I know they don't,
" said Harry. "
It was only a dream."
But he wished he hadn't said anything.
If there was one thing the Dursleys hated
even more than his asking questions,
it was his talking about anything
acting in a way it shouldn't,
no matter if it was in a dream or even a cartoon ,
they seemed to think he might get dangerous ideas.
It was a very sunny Saturday and
the zoo was crowded with families.
The Dursleys bought Dudley and Piers large
chocolate ice creams at the entrance and then,
because the smiling lady
in the van had asked Harry
what he wanted before they could hurry him away,
they bought him a cheap lemon ice pop.
It wasn't bad,
either, Harry thought,
licking it as they watched a
gorilla scratching its head
who looked remarkably like Dudley,
except that it wasn't blond.
Harry had the best morning
he'd had in a long time.
He was careful to walk a little way apart
from the Dursleys so that Dudley and Piers,
who were starting to get bored
with the animals by lunchtime,
wouldn't fall back on their
favorite hobby of hitting him.
They ate in the zoo restaurant,
and when Dudley had a tantrum
because his knickerbocker glory
didn't have enough ice cream on top,
Uncle Vernon bought him another one and
Harry was allowed to finish the first.
Harry felt,
afterward, that he should have
known it was all too good to last.
After lunch they went to the reptile house.
It was cool and dark in there,
with lit windows all along the walls.
Behind the glass,
all sorts of lizards and snakes were crawling
and slithering over bits of wood and stone.
Dudley and Piers wanted to see huge,
poisonous cobras and thick,
man-crushing pythons.
Dudley quickly found the
largest snake in the place.
It could have wrapped its body
twice around Uncle Vernon's car
and crushed it into a trash can ,
but at the moment it didn't look in the mood.
In fact, it was fast asleep.
Dudley stood with his nose
pressed against the glass,
staring at the glistening brown coils.
"Make it move,"
he whined at his father.
Uncle Vernon tapped on the glass,
but the snake didn't budge.
"Do it again,"
Dudley ordered.
Uncle Vernon rapped the glass
smartly with his knuckles,
but the snake just snoozed on.
"This is boring,"
Dudley moaned. He shuffled away.
Harry moved in front of the tank
and looked intently at the snake.
He wouldn't have been surprised
if it had died of boredom itself ,
no company except stupid
people drumming their fingers
on the glass trying to disturb it all day long.
It was worse than having a cupboard as a bedroom,
where the only visitor was Aunt Petunia
hammering on the door to wake you up;
at least he got to visit the rest of the house.
The snake suddenly opened its beady eyes.
Slowly, very slowly,
it raised its head until its eyes were
on a level with Harry's. It winked.
Harry stared.
Then he looked quickly around
to see if anyone was watching.
They weren't.
He looked back at the snake and winked, too.
The snake jerked its head
toward Uncle Vernon and Dudley,
then raised its eyes to the ceiling.
It gave Harry a look that said quite plainly:
"I get that all the time.
"I know,"
Harry murmured through the glass,
though he wasn't sure the snake could hear him.
"It must be really annoying."
The snake nodded vigorously.
"Where do you come from, anyway?"
Harry asked.
The snake jabbed its tail at a
little sign next to the glass.
Harry peered at it.
Boa Constrictor, Brazil.
"Was it nice there?"
The boa constrictor jabbed
its tail at the sign again
and Harry read on: This
specimen was bred in the zoo.
"Oh, I see , so you've never been to Brazil?"
As the snake shook its head,
a deafening shout behind Harry
made both of them jump. "DUDLEY!
MR. DURSLEY!
COME AND LOOK AT THIS SNAKE!
YOU WON'T BELIEVE WHAT IT'S DOING!"
Dudley came waddling toward
them as fast as he could.
"Out of the way, you,"
he said, punching Harry in the ribs.
Caught by surprise,
Harry fell hard on the concrete floor.
What came next happened so fast
no one saw how it happened ,
one second,
Piers and Dudley were leaning
right up close to the glass,
the next, they had leapt
back with howls of horror.
Harry sat up and gasped;
the glass front of the boa
constrictor's tank had vanished.
The great snake was uncoiling itself rapidly,
slithering out onto the floor.
People throughout the reptile house
screamed and started running for the exits.
As the snake slid swiftly past him,
Harry could have sworn a low,
hissing voice said,
"Brazil, here I come.... Thanksss, amigo."
The keeper of the reptile house was in shock.
"But the glass,"
he kept saying,
"where did the glass go?"
The zoo director himself made
Aunt Petunia a cup of strong,
sweet tea while he apologized over and over again.
Piers and Dudley could only gibber.
As far as Harry had seen,
the snake hadn't done anything except snap
playfully at their heels as it passed,
but by the time they were all
back in Uncle Vernon's car,
Dudley was telling them how it
had nearly bitten off his leg,
while Piers was swearing it had
tried to squeeze him to death.
But worst of all,
for Harry at least,
was Piers calming down enough to say,
"Harry was talking to it, weren't you, Harry?"
Uncle Vernon waited until Piers was safely
out of the house before starting on Harry.
He was so angry he could hardly speak.
He managed to say,
"Go , cupboard , stay , no meals,"
before he collapsed into a chair,
and Aunt Petunia had to run
and get him a large brandy.
Harry lay in his dark cupboard much later,
wishing he had a watch.
He didn't know what time it was and he
couldn't be sure the Dursleys were asleep yet.
Until they were,
he couldn't risk sneaking to
the kitchen for some food.
He'd lived with the Dursleys almost ten years,
ten miserable years,
as long as he could remember,
ever since he'd been a baby and his
parents had died in that car crash.
He couldn't remember being in the
car when his parents had died.
Sometimes, when he strained his memory
during long hours in his cupboard,
he came up with a strange vision:
a blinding flash of green light
and a burn- ing pain on his forehead.
This, he supposed,
was the crash,
though he couldn't imagine where
all the green light came from.
He couldn't remember his parents at all.
His aunt and uncle never spoke about them,
and of course he was forbidden to ask questions.
There were no photographs of them in the house.
When he had been younger,
Harry had dreamed and dreamed of some
unknown relation coming to take him away,
but it had never happened;
the Dursleys were his only family.
Yet sometimes he thought (or maybe hoped) that
strangers in the street seemed to know him.
Very strange strangers they were, too.
A tiny man in a violet top hat had bowed to
him once while out shopping with Aunt Petunia
and Dudley.
After asking Harry furiously if he knew the man,
Aunt Petunia had rushed them out of
the shop without buying anything.
A wild-looking old woman dressed all in
green had waved merrily at him once on a bus.
A bald man in a very long purple
coat had actually shaken his hand
in the street the other day
and then walked away without a word.
The weirdest thing about
all these people was the way
they seemed to vanish the second
Harry tried to get a closer look.
At school, Harry had no one.
Everybody knew that Dudley's gang hated that
odd Harry Potter in his baggy old clothes
and broken glasses,
and nobody liked to disagree with Dudley's gang.
CHAPTER THREE
THE LETTERS FROM NO ONE
The escape of the Brazilian boa constrictor
earned Harry his longest-ever punishment.
By the time he was allowed
out of his cupboard again,
the summer holidays had started and Dudley
had already broken his new video camera,
crashed his remote control airplane,
and, first time out on his racing bike,
knocked down old Mrs. Figg as she
crossed Privet Drive on her crutches.
Harry was glad school was over,
but there was no escaping Dudley's gang,
who visited the house every single day.
Piers, Dennis,
Malcolm, and Gordon were all big and stupid,
but as Dudley was the biggest
and stupidest of the lot,
he was the leader.
The rest of them were all quite happy to join
in Dudley's favorite sport: Harry Hunting.
This was why Harry spent as much
time as possible out of the house,
wandering around and thinking
about the end of the holidays,
where he could see a tiny ray of hope.
When September came he would be
going off to secondary school and,
for the first time in his life,
he wouldn't be with Dudley.
Dudley had been accepted at Uncle
Vernon's old private school, Smeltings.
Piers Polkiss was going there too.
Harry, on the other hand,
was going to Stonewall High,
the local public school.
Dudley thought this was very funny.
"They stuff people's heads down the
toilet the first day at Stonewall,"
he told Harry.
"Want to come upstairs and practice?"
"No, thanks,"
said Harry.
"The poor toilet's never had anything
as horrible as your head down it ,
it might be sick."
Then he ran, before Dudley
could work out what he'd said.
One day in July,
Aunt Petunia took Dudley to London
to buy his Smeltings uniform,
leaving Harry at Mrs. Figg's.
Mrs. Figg wasn 't as bad as usual.
It turned out she'd broken her
leg tripping over one of her cats,
and she didn't seem quite
as fond of them as before.
She let Harry watch television
and gave him a bit of chocolate cake that
tasted as though she'd had it for several years.
That evening,
Dudley paraded around the living room
for the family in his brand-new uniform.
Smeltings' boys wore maroon tailcoats,
orange knickerbockers,
and flat straw hats called boaters.
They also carried knobbly sticks,
used for hitting each other while
the teachers weren't looking.
This was supposed to be good
training for later life.
As he looked at Dudley in his new knickerbockers,
Uncle Vernon said gruffly that it
was the proudest moment of his life.
Aunt Petunia burst into tears and said she
couldn't believe it was her Ickle Dudleykins,
he looked so handsome and grown-up.
Harry didn't trust himself to speak.
He thought two of his ribs might already
have cracked from trying not to laugh.
There was a horrible smell in
the kitchen the next morning
when Harry went in for breakfast.
It seemed to be coming from a
large metal tub in the sink.
He went to have a look.
The tub was full of what looked like
dirty rags swimming in gray water.
"What's this?"
he asked Aunt Petunia.
Her lips tightened as they always
did if he dared to ask a question.
"Your new school uniform," she said.
Harry looked in the bowl again.
"Oh,"
he said, "I didn't realize it had to be so wet."
"DotA be stupid,"
snapped Aunt Petunia.
"I'm dyeing some of Dudley's
old things gray for you.
It'll look just like everyone
else's when I've finished."
Harry seriously doubted this,
but thought it best not to argue.
He sat down at the table
and tried not to think about
how he was going to look on his
first day at Stonewall High ,
like he was wearing bits of
old elephant skin, probably.
Dudley and Uncle Vernon came in,
both with wrinkled noses because of
the smell from Harry's new uniform.
Uncle Vernon opened his newspaper as usual
and Dudley banged his Smelting stick,
which he carried everywhere,
on the table.
They heard the click of the mail slot
and flop of letters on the doormat.
"Get the mail, Dudley,"
said Uncle Vernon from behind his paper.
"Make Harry get it."
"Get the mail, Harry."
"Make Dudley get it."
"Poke him with your Smelting stick, Dudley."
Harry dodged the Smelting
stick and went to get the mail.
Three things lay on the doormat: a
postcard from Uncle Vernon's sister Marge,
who was vacationing on the Isle of Wight,
a brown envelope that looked like a bill,
and , a letter for Harry.
Harry picked it up and stared at it,
his heart twanging like a giant elastic band.
No one, ever,
in his whole life,
had written to him. Who would?
He had no friends,
no other relatives ,
he didn't belong to the library,
so he'd never even got rude
notes asking for books back.
Yet here it was,
a letter, addressed so plainly
there could be no mistake:
Mr. H. Potter
The Cupboard under the Stairs
4 Privet Drive
Little Whinging
Surrey
The envelope was thick and heavy,
made of yellowish parchment,
and the address was written in emerald-green ink.
There was no stamp.
Turning the envelope over,
his hand trembling,
Harry saw a purple wax seal
bearing a coat of arms;
a lion, an eagle,
a badger, and a snake
surrounding a large letter H.
"Hurry up, boy!"
shouted Uncle Vernon from the kitchen.
"What are you doing, checking for letter bombs?"
He chuckled at his own joke.
Harry went back to the kitchen,
still staring at his letter.
He handed Uncle Vernon the bill and the postcard,
sat down, and slowly began
to open the yellow envelope.
Uncle Vernon ripped open the bill,
snorted in disgust,
and flipped over the postcard.
"Marge's ill,"
he informed Aunt Petunia.
"Ate a funny whelk. , ."
"Dad!"
said Dudley suddenly.
"Dad, Harry's got something!"
Harry was on the point of unfolding his letter,
which was written on the same
heavy parchment as the envelope,
when it was jerked sharply out
of his hand by Uncle Vernon.
"That's mine!"
said Harry, trying to snatch it back.
"Who'd be writing to you?"
sneered Uncle Vernon,
shaking the letter open with
one hand and glancing at it.
His face went from red to green
faster than a set of traffic lights.
And it didn't stop there.
Within seconds it was the
grayish white of old porridge.
"P-P-Petunia!" he gasped.
Dudley tried to grab the letter to read it,
but Uncle Vernon held it high out of his reach.
Aunt Petunia took it curiously
and read the first line.
For a moment it looked as though she might faint.
She clutched her throat and made a choking noise.
"Vernon! Oh my goodness , Vernon!"
They stared at each other,
seeming to have forgotten that Harry
and Dudley were still in the room.
Dudley wasn't used to being ignored.
He gave his father a sharp tap on
the head with his Smelting stick.
"I want to read that letter,"
he said loudly. want to read it,
" said Harry furiously, "
as it's mine."
"Get out, both of you,"
croaked Uncle Vernon, stuffing the
letter back inside its envelope.
Harry didn't move.
I WANT MY LETTER!" he shouted.
"Let me see it!"
demanded Dudley.
"OUT!"
roared Uncle Vernon,
and he took both Harry
and Dudley by the scruffs of their
necks and threw them into the hall,
slamming the kitchen door behind them.
Harry and Dudley promptly had
a furious but silent fight over
who would listen at the keyhole;
Dudley won,
so Harry, his glasses dangling from one ear,
lay flat on his stomach to listen
at the crack between door and floor.
"Vernon,"
Aunt Petunia was saying in a quivering voice,
"look at the address ,
how could they possibly know where he sleeps?
You don't think they're watching the house?"
"Watching , spying , might be following us,"
muttered Uncle Vernon wildly.
"But what should we do, Vernon?
Should we write back?
Tell them we don't want ,
"
Harry could see Uncle Vernon's shiny black
shoes pacing up and down the kitchen.
"No,"
he said finally.
"No, we'll ignore it.
If they don't get an answer...
Yes, that's best...
we won't do anything....
"But , "
"I'm not having one in the house, Petunia!
Didn't we swear when we took him in
we'd stamp out that dangerous nonsense?"
That evening when he got back from work,
Uncle Vernon did something he'd never done before;
he visited Harry in his cupboard.
"Where's my letter?"
said Harry, the moment Uncle Vernon
had squeezed through the door.
"Who's writing to me?"
"No one. it was addressed to you by mistake,"
said Uncle Vernon shortly.
"I have burned it."
"It was not a mistake,"
said Harry angrily,
"it had my cupboard on it."
"SILENCE!"
yelled Uncle Vernon,
and a couple of spiders fell from the ceiling.
He took a few deep breaths and
then forced his face into a smile,
which looked quite painful.
"Er , yes, Harry , about this cupboard.
Your aunt and I have been thinking...
you're really getting a bit big for it...
we think it might be nice if you
moved into Dudley's second bedroom.
"Why?"
said Harry.
"Don't ask questions!"
snapped his uncle.
"Take this stuff upstairs, now."
The Dursleys' house had four bedrooms:
one for Uncle Vernon and Aunt Petunia,
one for visitors (usually Uncle Vernon's sister,
Marge), one where Dudley slept,
and one where Dudley kept all the toys
and things that wouldn't
fit into his first bedroom.
It only took Harry one trip
upstairs to move everything he owned
from the cupboard to this room.
He sat down on the bed and stared around him.
Nearly everything in here was broken.
The month-old video camera
was lying on top of a small,
working tank Dudley had once driven
over the next door neighbor's dog;
in the corner was Dudley's
first-ever television set,
which he'd put his foot through when
his favorite program had been canceled;
there was a large birdcage,
which had once held a parrot that Dudley
had swapped at school for a real air rifle,
which was up on a shelf with the end
all bent because Dudley had sat on it.
Other shelves were full of books.
They were the only things in the room that
looked as though they'd never been touched.
From downstairs came the sound
of Dudley bawling at his mother,
I don't want him in there...
I need that room...
make him get out...."
Harry sighed and stretched out on the bed.
Yesterday he'd have given anything to be up here.
Today he'd rather be back in his cupboard
with that letter than up here without it.
Next morning at breakfast,
everyone was rather quiet.
Dudley was in shock.
He'd screamed,
whacked his father with his Smelting stick,
been sick on purpose,
kicked his mother,
and thrown his tortoise
through the greenhouse roof,
and he still didn't have his room back.
Harry was thinking about this time yesterday
and bitterly wishing he'd
opened the letter in the hall.
Uncle Vernon and Aunt Petunia
kept looking at each other darkly.
When the mail arrived,
Uncle Vernon,
who seemed to be trying to be nice to Harry,
made Dudley go and get it.
They heard him banging things with his
Smelting stick all the way down the hall.
Then he shouted,
"There's another one! 'Mr. H.
Potter, The Smallest Bedroom,
4 Privet Drive ,
'"
With a strangled cry,
Uncle Vernon leapt from his
seat and ran down the hall,
Harry right behind him.
Uncle Vernon had to wrestle Dudley to
the ground to get the letter from him,
which was made difficult
by the fact that Harry had grabbed Uncle
Vernon around the neck from behind.
After a minute of confused fighting,
in which everyone got hit a
lot by the Smelting stick,
Uncle Vernon straightened up,
gasping for breath,
with Harry's letter clutched in his hand.
"Go to your cupboard , I mean, your bedroom,"
he wheezed at Harry.
"Dudley , go , just go."
Harry walked round and round his new room.
Someone knew he had moved out of his cupboard
and they seemed to know he
hadn't received his first letter.
Surely that meant they'd try again?
And this time he'd make sure they didn't fail.
He had a plan.
The repaired alarm clock rang
at six o'clock the next morning.
Harry turned it off quickly and dressed silently.
He mustn't wake the Dursleys.
He stole downstairs without
turning on any of the lights.
He was going to wait for the postman
on the corner of Privet Drive
and get the letters for number four first.
His heart hammered as he crept across
the dark hall toward the front door ,
Harry leapt into the air;
he'd trodden on something big
and squashy on the doormat ,
something alive!
Lights clicked on upstairs and to his
horror Harry realized that the big,
squashy something had been his uncle's face.
Uncle Vernon had been lying at the foot
of the front door in a sleeping bag,
clearly making sure that Harry didn't
do exactly what he'd been trying to do.
He shouted at Harry for about half an hour
and then told him to go and make a cup of tea.
Harry shuffled miserably off into the
kitchen and by the time he got back,
the mail had arrived,
right into Uncle Vernon's lap.
Harry could see three letters
addressed in green ink.
I want , " he began,
but Uncle Vernon was tearing the
letters into pieces before his eyes.
Uncle Vernon didnt go to work that day.
He stayed at home and nailed up the mail slot.
"See,"
he explained to Aunt Petunia
through a mouthful of nails,
"if they can't deliver them they'll just give up."
"I'm not sure that'll work, Vernon."
"Oh, these people's minds work in strange ways,
Petunia, they're not like you and me,"
said Uncle Vernon,
trying to knock in a nail with the piece of
fruitcake Aunt Petunia had just brought him.
On Friday, no less than twelve
letters arrived for Harry.
As they couldn't go through the mail
slot they had been pushed under the door,
slotted through the sides,
and a few even forced through the small
window in the downstairs bathroom.
Uncle Vernon stayed at home again.
After burning all the letters,
he got out a hammer and nails
and boarded up the cracks around the front
and back doors so no one could go out.
He hummed
"Tiptoe Through the Tulips"
as he worked, and jumped at small noises.
On Saturday,
things began to get out of hand.
Twenty-four letters to Harry
found their way into the house,
rolled up and hidden inside
each of the two dozen eggs
that their very confused milkman had handed
Aunt Petunia through the living room window.
While Uncle Vernon made furious
telephone calls to the post office
and the dairy trying to
find someone to complain to,
Aunt Petunia shredded the
letters in her food processor.
"Who on earth wants to talk to you this badly?"
Dudley asked Harry in amazement.
On Sunday morning,
Uncle Vernon sat down at the breakfast table
looking tired and rather ill, but happy.
"No post on Sundays,"
he reminded them cheerfully as he
spread marmalade on his newspapers,
"no damn letters today , "
Something came whizzing down
the kitchen chimney as he spoke
and caught him sharply on the back of the head.
Next moment,
thirty or forty letters came pelting
out of the fireplace like bullets.
The Dursleys ducked,
but Harry leapt into the air trying to catch one.
"Out! OUT!"
Uncle Vernon seized Harry around the
waist and threw him into the hall.
When Aunt Petunia and Dudley had run
out with their arms over their faces,
Uncle Vernon slammed the door shut.
They could hear the letters
still streaming into the room,
bouncing off the walls and floor.
"That does it,"
said Uncle Vernon,
trying to speak calmly but pulling great
tufts out of his mustache at the same time.
I want you all back here in
five minutes ready to leave.
We're going away.
Just pack some clothes.
No arguments!"
He looked so dangerous with half his
mustache missing that no one dared argue.
Ten minutes later they had wrenched
their way through the boarded-up doors
and were in the car,
speeding toward the highway.
Dudley was sniffling in the back seat;
his father had hit him round the head
for holding them up while he tried
to pack his television,
VCR, and computer in his sports bag.
They drove.
And they drove.
Even Aunt Petunia didn't dare
ask where they were going.
Every now and then Uncle
Vernon would take a sharp turn
and drive in the opposite direction for a while.
"Shake'em off... shake 'em off,"
he would mutter whenever he did this.
They didn't stop to eat or drink all day.
By nightfall Dudley was howling.
He'd never had such a bad day in his life.
He was hungry,
he'd missed five television
programs he'd wanted to see,
and he'd never gone so long without
blowing up an alien on his computer.
Uncle Vernon stopped at last
outside a gloomy-looking hotel
on the outskirts of a big city.
Dudley and Harry shared a
room with twin beds and damp,
musty sheets.
Dudley snored but Harry stayed awake,
sitting on the windowsill,
staring down at the lights of
passing cars and wondering....
They ate stale cornflakes and cold tinned
tomatoes on toast for breakfast the next day.
They had just finished when the owner
of the hotel came over to their table.
"'Scuse me,
but is one of you Mr. H. Potter?
Only I got about an 'undred
of these at the front desk."
She held up a letter so they
could read the green ink address:
Mr. H. Potter
Room 17
Railview Hotel
Cokeworth
Harry made a grab for the letter but Uncle
Vernon knocked his hand out of the way.
The woman stared.
"I'll take them,"
said Uncle Vernon,
standing up quickly and following
her from the dining room.
Wouldn't it be better just to go home,
dear?" Aunt Petunia suggested timidly,
hours later,
but Uncle Vernon didn't seem to hear her.
Exactly what he was looking for,
none of them knew.
He drove them into the middle of a forest,
got out, looked around,
shook his head,
got back in the car,
and off they went again.
The same thing happened in
the middle of a plowed field,
halfway across a suspension bridge,
and at the top of a multilevel parking garage.
"Daddy's gone mad, hasn't he?"
Dudley asked Aunt Petunia
dully late that afternoon.
Uncle Vernon had parked at the coast,
locked them all inside the car,
and disappeared.
It started to rain.
Great drops beat on the roof of the car.
Dud ley sniveled.
"It's Monday,"
he told his mother.
"The Great Humberto's on tonight.
I want to stay somewhere
with a television. " Monday.
This reminded Harry of something.
If it was Monday ,
and you could usually count on
Dudley to know the days the week,
because of television ,
then tomorrow,
Tuesday, was Harry's eleventh birthday.
Of course, his birthdays were never exactly fun ,
last year, the Dursleys had given him a coat
hanger and a pair of Uncle Vernon's old socks.
Still, you weren't eleven every day.
Uncle Vernon was back and he was smiling.
He was also carrying a long,
thin package and didn't answer Aunt
Petunia when she asked what he'd bought.
"Found the perfect place!" he said.
"Come on! Everyone out!"
It was very cold outside the car.
Uncle Vernon was pointing at what
looked like a large rock way out at sea.
Perched on top of the rock was the most
miserable little shack you could imagine.
One thing was certain,
there was no television in there.
"Storm forecast for tonight!"
said Uncle Vernon gleefully,
clapping his hands together.
"And this gentleman's kindly
agreed to lend us his boat!"
A toothless old man came ambling up to them,
pointing, with a rather wicked grin,
at an old rowboat bobbing in
the iron-gray water below them.
"I've already got us some rations,"
said Uncle Vernon,
"so all aboard!"
It was freezing in the boat.
Icy sea spray and rain crept down their
necks and a chilly wind whipped their faces.
After what seemed like
hours they reached the rock,
where Uncle Vernon,
slipping and sliding,
led the way to the broken-down house.
The inside was horrible;
it smelled strongly of seaweed,
the wind whistled through
the gaps in the wooden walls,
and the fireplace was damp and empty.
There were only two rooms.
Uncle Vernon's rations turned out to be
a bag of chips each and four bananas.
He tried to start a fire but the empty
chip bags just smoked and shriveled up.
"Could do with some of those letters now, eh?"
he said cheerfully.
He was in a very good mood.
Obviously he thought nobody stood
a chance of reaching them here
in a storm to deliver mail.
Harry privately agreed,
though the thought didn't cheer him up at all.
As night fell,
the promised storm blew up around them.
Spray from the high waves
splattered the walls of the hut
and a fierce wind rattled the filthy windows.
Aunt Petunia found a few moldy
blankets in the second room
and made up a bed for Dudley
on the moth-eaten sofa.
She and Uncle Vernon went off
to the lumpy bed next door,
and Harry was left to find the
softest bit of floor he could
and to curl up under the thinnest,
most ragged blanket.
The storm raged more and more
ferociously as the night went on.
Harry couldn't sleep.
He shivered and turned over,
trying to get comfortable,
his stomach rumbling with hunger.
Dudley's snores were drowned by the low
rolls of thunder that started near midnight.
The lighted dial of Dudley's watch,
which was dangling over the edge
of the sofa on his fat wrist,
told Harry he'd be eleven in ten minutes' time.
He lay and watched his birthday tick nearer,
wondering if the Dursleys would remember at all,
wondering where the letter writer was now.
Five minutes to go.
Harry heard something creak outside.
He hoped the roof wasn't going to fall in,
although he might be warmer if it did.
Four minutes to go.
Maybe the house in Privet Drive
would be so full of letters
when they got back that he'd
be able to steal one somehow.
Three minutes to go.
Was that the sea,
slapping hard on the rock like that?
And (two minutes to go) what
was that funny crunching noise?
Was the rock crumbling into the sea?
One minute to go and he'd be eleven.
Thirty seconds... twenty ... ten...
nine , maybe he'd wake Dudley up,
just to annoy him , three...
two... one... BOOM.
The whole shack shivered
and Harry sat bolt upright,
staring at the door.
Someone was outside,
knocking to come in.
CHAPTER FOUR
THE KEEPER OF THE KEYS
BOOM. They knocked again. Dudley jerked awake.
"Where's the cannon?"
he said stupidly.
There was a crash behind them and Uncle
Vernon came skidding into the room.
He was holding a rifle in his hands ,
now they knew what had been in the long,
thin package he had brought with them.
"Who's there?"
he shouted.
"I warn you , I'm armed!"
There was a pause. Then , SMASH!
The door was hit with such force
that it swung clean off its hinges
and with a deafening crash
landed flat on the floor.
A giant of a man was standing in the doorway.
His face was almost completely hidden by a long,
shaggy mane of hair and a wild,
tangled beard,
but you could make out his eyes,
glinting like black beetles under all the hair.
The giant squeezed his way into the hut,
stooping so that his head
just brushed the ceiling.
He bent down,
picked up the door,
and fitted it easily back into its frame.
The noise of the storm outside dropped a little.
He turned to look at them all.
"Couldn't make us a cup o' tea, could yeh?
It's not been an easy journey..."
He strode over to the sofa where
Dudley sat frozen with fear.
"Budge up, yeh great lump,"
said the stranger.
Dudley squeaked and ran to hide behind his mother,
who was crouching,
terrified, behind Uncle Vernon.
"An' here's Harry!"
said the giant.
Harry looked up into the fierce,
wild, shadowy face and saw that the
beetle eyes were crinkled in a smile.
"Las' time I saw you, you was only a baby,"
said the giant.
"Yeh look a lot like yet dad,
but yeh've got yet mom's eyes."
Uncle Vernon made a funny rasping noise.
I demand that you leave at once, sit!
" he said. "
You are breaking and entering!"
"Ah, shut up, Dursley, yeh great prune,"
said the giant;
he reached over the back of the sofa,
jerked the gun out of Uncle Vernon's hands,
bent it into a knot as easily as
if it had been made of rubber,
and threw it into a corner of the room.
Uncle Vernon made another funny
noise, like a mouse being trodden on.
"Anyway , Harry,"
said the giant, turning his back on the Dursleys,
"a very happy birthday to yeh.
Got summat fer yeh here ,
I mighta sat on it at some point,
but it'll taste all right."
From an inside pocket of his black
overcoat he pulled a slightly squashed box.
Harry opened it with trembling fingers.
Inside was a large,
sticky chocolate cake with Happy Birthday
Harry written on it in green icing.
Harry looked up at the giant.
He meant to say thank you,
but the words got lost on the way to his mouth,
and what he said instead was,
"Who are you?"
The giant chuckled.
"True, I haven't introduced meself.
Rubeus Hagrid,
Keeper of Keys and Grounds at Hogwarts."
He held out an enormous hand
and shook Harry's whole arm.
"What about that tea then, eh?"
he said, rubbing his hands together.
"I'd not say no ter summat
stronger if yeh've got it, mind."
His eyes fell on the empty grate with the
shriveled chip bags in it and he snorted.
He bent down over the fireplace;
they couldn't see what he was doing
but when he drew back a second later,
there was a roaring fire there.
It filled the whole damp hut with flickering light
and Harry felt the warmth wash over him
as though he'd sunk into a hot bath.
The giant sat back down on the sofa,
which sagged under his weight,
and began taking all sorts of things out of
the pockets of his coat: a copper kettle,
a squashy package of sausages,
a poker, a teapot,
several chipped mugs,
and a bottle of some amber liquid that he
took a swig from before starting to make tea.
Soon the hut was full of the sound
and smell of sizzling sausage.
Nobody said a thing while the giant was working,
but as he slid the first six fat,
juicy, slightly burnt sausages from the poker,
Dudley fidgeted a little.
Uncle Vernon said sharply,
"Don't touch anything he gives you, Dudley."
The giant chuckled darkly.
"Yet great puddin' of a son
don' need fattenin' anymore,
Dursley, don' worry."
He passed the sausages to Harry,
who was so hungry he had never
tasted anything so wonderful,
but he still couldn't take his eyes off the giant.
Finally, as nobody seemed
about to explain anything,
he said, "I'm sorry, but I still
don't really know who you are."
The giant took a gulp of tea and wiped
his mouth with the back of his hand.
"Call me Hagrid,"
he said, "everyone does.
An' like I told yeh,
I'm Keeper of Keys at Hogwarts ,
yeh'll know all about Hogwarts, o' course.
"Er , no,"
said Harry.
Hagrid looked shocked.
"Sorry,"
Harry said quickly.
"Sony?"
barked Hagrid,
turning to stare at the Dursleys,
who shrank back into the shadows.
"It' s them as should be sorry!
I knew yeh weren't gettin' yer letters but
I never thought yeh wouldn't
even know abou' Hogwarts,
fer cryin' out loud!
Did yeh never wonder where
yet parents learned it all?"
"All what?"
asked Harry.
"ALL WHAT?"
Hagrid thundered.
"Now wait jus' one second!"
He had leapt to his feet.
In his anger he seemed to fill the whole hut.
The Dursleys were cowering against the wall.
"Do you mean ter tell me,"
he growled at the Dursleys,
"that this boy , this boy! , knows
nothin' abou' , about ANYTHING?"
Harry thought this was going a bit far.
He had been to school,
after all, and his marks weren't bad.
"I know some things," he said.
"I can, you know, do math and stuff."
But Hagrid simply waved his hand and said,
"About our world, I mean. Your
world. My world. Yer parents' world."
"What world?"
Hagrid looked as if he was about to explode.
"DURSLEY!" he boomed.
Uncle Vernon,
who had gone very pale,
whispered something that sounded like
"Mimblewimble."
Hagrid stared wildly at Harry.
"But yeh must know about
yet mom and dad," he said.
"I mean, they're famous. You're famous."
"What? My , my mom and dad
weren't famous, were they?"
"Yeh don' know... yeh don' know..."
Hagrid ran his fingers through his hair,
fixing Harry with a bewildered stare.
"Yeh don' know what yeh are?"
he said finally.
Uncle Vernon suddenly found his voice.
"Stop!"
he commanded.
"Stop right there, sit! I forbid
you to tell the boy anything!"
A braver man than Vernon
Dursley would have quailed
under the furious look Hagrid now gave him;
when Hagrid spoke,
his every syllable trembled with rage.
"You never told him?
Never told him what was in the
letter Dumbledore left fer him?
I was there!
I saw Dumbledore leave it, Dursley!
An' you've kept it from him all these years?"
"Kept what from me?"
said Harry eagerly.
"STOP! I FORBID YOU!"
yelled Uncle Vernon in panic.
Aunt Petunia gave a gasp of horror.
"Ah, go boil yet heads, both of yeh,"
said Hagrid.
"Harry , yet a wizard."
There was silence inside the hut.
Only the sea and the
whistling wind could be heard.
", a what?"
gasped Harry.
"A wizard, o' course,"
said Hagrid,
sitting back down on the sofa,
which groaned and sank even lower,
"an' a thumpin' good'un,
I'd say, once yeh've been trained up a bit.
With a mum an' dad like yours,
what else would yeh be?
An' I reckon it's abou' time yeh read yer letter."
Harry stretched out his hand at
last to take the yellowish envelope,
addressed in emerald green to Mr. H.
Potter, The Floor,
Hut-on-the-Rock, The Sea.
He pulled out the letter and read:
HOGWARTS SCHOOL of WITCHCRAFT and WIZARDRY
Headmaster: ALBUS DUMBLEDORE
(Order of Merlin,
First Class,
Grand Sorc., Chf.
Warlock, Supreme Mugwump,
International Confed.
of Wizards)
Dear Mr. Potter,
We are pleased to inform you that you have
been accepted at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft
and Wizardry.
Please find enclosed a list of
all necessary books and equipment.
Term begins on September 1.
We await your owl by no later than July 31.
Yours sincerely,
Minerva McGonagall,
Deputy Headmistress
Questions exploded inside Harry's head
like fireworks and he couldn't decide
which to ask first.
After a few minutes he stammered,
"What does it mean, they await my owl?"
"Gallopin' Gorgons, that reminds me,"
said Hagrid,
clapping a hand to his forehead with
enough force to knock over a cart horse,
and from yet another pocket inside
his overcoat he pulled an owl ,
a real, live,
rather ruffled-looking owl ,
a long quill,
and a roll of parchment.
With his tongue between his teeth he scribbled
a note that Harry could read upside down:
Dear Professor Dumbledore,
Given Harry his letter.
Taking him to buy his things tomorrow.
Weather's horrible. Hope you're Well.
Hagrid
Hagrid rolled up the note,
gave it to the owl,
which clamped it in its beak,
went to the door,
and threw the owl out into the storm.
Then he came back and sat down as though this
was as normal as talking on the telephone.
Harry realized his mouth was
open and closed it quickly.
"Where was I?"
said Hagrid,
but at that moment,
Uncle Vernon,
still ashen-faced but looking very angry,
moved into the firelight.
"He's not going," he said.
Hagrid grunted.
"I'd like ter see a great Muggle
like you stop him," he said.
"A what?"
said Harry, interested.
"A Muggle,"
said Hagrid,
"it's what we call nonmagic folk like thern.
An' it's your bad luck you grew up
in a family o' the biggest Muggles
I ever laid eyes on."
"We swore when we took him in
we'd put a stop to that rubbish,"
said Uncle Vernon,
"swore we'd stamp it out of him! Wizard indeed!"
"You knew?"
said Harry.
"You knew I'm a , a wizard?"
"Knew!"
shrieked Aunt Petunia suddenly. "Knew!
Of course we knew!
How could you not be,
my dratted sister being what she was?
Oh, she got a letter just like that
and disappeared off to that-that
school-and came home every vacation
with her pockets full of frog spawn,
turning teacups into rats.
I was the only one who saw her
for what she was , a freak!
But for my mother and father,
oh no, it was Lily this and Lily that,
they were proud of having a witch in the family!"
She stopped to draw a deep
breath and then went ranting on.
It seemed she had been wanting
to say all this for years.
"Then she met that Potter at school and
they left and got married and had you,
and of course I knew you'd be just the same,
just as strange,
just as , as ,
abnormal , and then,
if you please,
she went and got herself blown
up and we got landed with you!"
Harry had gone very white. As soon
as he found his voice he said,
"Blown up? You told me they died in a car crash!"
"CAR CRASH!"
roared Hagrid,
jumping up so angrily that the
Dursleys scuttled back to their corner.
"How could a car crash kill Lily an' James Potter?
It's an outrage! A scandal!
Harry Potter not knowin' his own story when
every kid in our world knows his name!"
"But why? What happened?"
Harry asked urgently.
The anger faded from Hagrid's
face. He looked suddenly anxious.
"I never expected this,"
he said, in a low, worried voice.
"I had no idea,
when Dumbledore told me there might
be trouble gettin' hold of yeh,
how much yeh didn't know.
Ah, Harry, I don' know if I'm
the right person ter tell yeh ,
but someone 3 s gotta ,
yeh can't go off ter Hogwarts not knowin'."
He threw a dirty look at the Dursleys.
"Well, it's best yeh know
as much as I can tell yeh ,
mind, I can't tell yeh everythin',
it's a great myst'ry,
parts of it...."
He sat down, stared into the fire
for a few seconds, and then said,
"It begins,
I suppose, with ,
with a person called ,
but it's incredible yeh don't know his name,
everyone in our world knows ,
"
"Who? "
"Well , I don' like sayin' the name
if I can help it. No one does."
"Why not?"
"Gulpin' gargoyles,
Harry, people are still scared.
Blimey, this is difficult.
See, there was this wizard who went... bad.
As bad as you could go. Worse.
Worse than worse.
His name was..."
Hagrid gulped, but no words came out.
"Could you write it down?"
Harry suggested.
"Nah -can't spell it. All right , Voldemort. "
Hagrid shuddered.
"Don' make me say it again.
Anyway, this ,
this wizard,
about twenty years ago now,
started lookin' fer followers.
Got 'em, too ,
some were afraid,
some just wanted a bit o' his power,
'cause he was gettin' himself power, all right.
Dark days, Harry.
Didn't know who ter trust,
didn't dare get friendly with
strange wizards or witches...
terrible things happened.
He was takin' over.
'Course, some stood up to him ,
an' he killed 'em. Horribly.
One o' the only safe places left was Hogwarts.
Reckon Dumbledore's the only
one You-Know-Who was afraid of.
Didn't dare try takin' the school,
not jus' then, anyway.
"Now, yer mum an' dad were as good
a witch an' wizard as I ever knew.
Head boy an' girl at Hogwarts in their day!
Suppose the myst'ry is why You-Know-Who
never tried to get 'em on his side before...
probably knew they were too close ter
Dumbledore ter want anythin' ter do
with the Dark Side.
"Maybe he thought he could persuade 'em...
maybe he just wanted 'em outta the way.
All anyone knows is,
he turned up in the village
where you was all living,
on Halloween ten years ago.
You was just a year old.
He came ter yer house an' ,
an' , "
Hagrid suddenly pulled out a very dirty,
spotted handkerchief and blew his
nose with a sound like a foghorn.
"Sorry," he said.
"But it's that sad ,
knew yer mum an' dad,
an' nicer people yeh couldn't find ,
anyway..."
"You-Know-Who killed 'em.
An' then , an' this is the
real myst'ry of the thing ,
he tried to kill you, too.
Wanted ter make a clean job of it,
I suppose, or maybe he just liked killin' by then.
But he couldn't do it.
Never wondered how you got
that mark on yer forehead?
That was no ordinary cut.
That's what yeh get when a Powerful,
evil curse touches yeh ,
took care of yer mum an' dad an' yer house,
even , but it didn't work on you,
an' that's why yer famous, Harry.
No one ever lived after he decided ter kill 'em,
no one except you,
an' he'd killed some o' the best
witches an' wizards of the age ,
the McKinnons,
the Bones, the Prewetts ,
an' you was only a baby,
an' you lived."
Something very painful was
going on in Harry's mind.
As Hagrid's story came to a close,
he saw again the blinding flash of green light,
more clearly than he had
ever remembered it before ,
and he remembered something else,
for the first time in his life: a high,
cold, cruel laugh.
Hagrid was watching him sadly.
"Took yeh from the ruined house myself,
on Dumbledore's orders.
Brought yeh ter this lot..."
"Load of old tosh,"
said Uncle Vernon.
Harry jumped;
he had almost forgotten that
the Dursleys were there.
Uncle Vernon certainly seemed
to have got back his courage.
He was glaring at Hagrid
and his fists were clenched.
"Now, you listen here, boy,"
he snarled,
"I accept there's something strange about you,
probably nothing a good
beating wouldn't have cured ,
and as for all this about your parents,
well, they were weirdos,
no denying it,
and the world's better off
without them in my opinion ,
asked for all they got,
getting mixed up with these wizarding types ,
just what I expected,
always knew they'd come to a sticky end ,
"
But at that moment,
Hagrid leapt from the sofa and drew a
battered pink umbrella from inside his coat.
Pointing this at Uncle Vernon like a sword,
he said, "I'm warning you, Dursley
-I'm warning you , one more word... "
In danger of being speared on the end
of an umbrella by a bearded giant,
Uncle Vernon's courage failed again;
he flattened himself against
the wall and fell silent.
"That's better,"
said Hagrid,
breathing heavily and sitting
back down on the sofa,
which this time sagged right down to the floor.
Harry, meanwhile, still had
questions to ask, hundreds of them.
"But what happened to Vol, ,
sorry , I mean, You-Know-Who?"
"Good question, Harry.
Disappeared. Vanished.
Same night he tried ter kill you.
Makes yeh even more famous.
That's the biggest myst'ry, see...
he was gettin' more an' more powerful ,
why'd he go?
"Some say he died.
Codswallop,
in my opinion.
Dunno if he had enough human left in him to die.
Some say he's still out there,
bidin' his time,
like, but I don' believe it.
People who was on his side came back ter ours.
Some of 'em came outta kinda trances.
Don~ reckon they could've
done if he was comin' back.
"Most of us reckon he's still out
there somewhere but lost his powers.
Too weak to carry on.
'Cause somethin' about you finished him, Harry.
There was somethin' goin' on
that night he hadn't counted on ,
I dunno what it was,
no one does ,
but somethin' about you stumped him,
all right."
Hagrid looked at Harry with warmth
and respect blazing in his eyes,
but Harry, instead of feeling pleased and proud,
felt quite sure there had been a
horrible mistake. A wizard? Him?
How could he possibly be?
He'd spent his life being clouted by Dudley,
and bullied by Aunt Petunia and Uncle Vernon;
if he was really a wizard,
why hadn't they been turned into warty
toads every time they'd tried to lock him
in his cupboard?
If he'd once defeated the
greatest sorcerer in the world,
how come Dudley had always been able
to kick him around like a football?
"Hagrid,"
he said quietly,
"I think you must have made a mistake.
I don't think I can be a wizard."
To his surprise, Hagrid chuckled.
"Not a wizard, eh?
Never made things happen when
you was scared or angry?"
Harry looked into the fire.
Now he came to think about it...
every odd thing that had ever made his aunt
and uncle furious with him had happened
when he, Harry,
had been upset or angry...
chased by Dudley's gang,
he had somehow found himself out of their reach...
dreading going to school
with that ridiculous haircut,
he'd managed to make it grow back...
and the very last time Dudley had hit him,
hadn't he got his revenge,
without even realizing he was doing it?
Hadn't he set a boa constrictor on him?
Harry looked back at Hagrid,
smiling, and saw that Hagrid
was positively beaming at him.
"See?"
said Hagrid.
"Harry Potter,
not a wizard ,
you wait, you'll be right famous at Hogwarts."
But Uncle Vernon wasn't going
to give in without a fight.
"Haven't I told you he's not going?" he hissed.
"He's going to Stonewall High
and he'll be grateful for it.
I've read those letters and he
needs all sorts of rubbish ,
spell books and wands and ,
"
"If he wants ter go, a great
Muggle like you won't stop him,"
growled Hagrid.
"Stop Lily an' James Potter' s
son goin' ter Hogwarts! Yer mad.
His name's been down ever since he was born.
He's off ter the finest school of
witchcraft and wizardry in the world.
Seven years there and he won't know himself.
He'll be with youngsters of his own sort,
fer a change,
an' he'll be under the greatest headmaster
Hogwarts ever had Albus Dumbled,
"
"I AM NOT PAYING FOR SOME CRACKPOT
OLD FOOL To TEACH HIM MAGIC TRICKS!"
yelled Uncle Vernon.
But he had finally gone too far.
Hagrid seized his umbrella
and whirled it over his head,
"NEVER,"
he thundered,
"- INSULT- ALBUS- DUMBLEDORE- IN- FRONT- OF- ME!"
He brought the umbrella swishing down
through the air to point at Dudley ,
there was a flash of violet light,
a sound like a firecracker,
a sharp squeal,
and the next second,
Dudley was dancing on the spot with
his hands clasped over his fat bottom,
howling in pain.
When he turned his back on them,
Harry saw a curly pig's tail poking
through a hole in his trousers.
Uncle Vernon roared.
Pulling Aunt Petunia and
Dudley into the other room,
he cast one last terrified look at
Hagrid and slammed the door behind them.
Hagrid looked down at his
umbrella and stroked his beard.
"Shouldn'ta lost me temper,"
he said ruefully,
"but it didn't work anyway.
Meant ter turn him into a pig,
but I suppose he was so much like a pig
anyway there wasn't much left ter do."
He cast a sideways look at
Harry under his bushy eyebrows.
"Be grateful if yeh didn't mention
that ter anyone at Hogwarts," he said.
"I'm , er ,
not supposed ter do magic,
strictly speakin'.
I was allowed ter do a bit ter follow yeh
an' get yer letters to yeh an' stuff ,
one o' the reasons I was
so keen ter take on the job
"Why aren't you supposed to do magic?"
asked Harry.
"Oh, well ,
I was at Hogwarts meself but I ,
er , got expelled,
ter tell yeh the truth.
In me third year.
They snapped me wand in half an' everything.
But Dumbledore let me stay on as gamekeeper.
Great man, Dumbledore."
"Why were you expelled?"
"It's gettin' late and we've
got lots ter do tomorrow,"
said Hagrid loudly.
"Gotta get up ter town, get
all yer books an' that."
He took off his thick black
coat and threw it to Harry.
"You can kip under that," he said.
"Don' mind if it wriggles a bit,
I think I still got a couple o'
dormice in one o' the pockets."
CHAPTER FIVE
DIAGON ALLEY
Harry woke early the next morning.
Although he could tell it was daylight,
he kept his eyes shut tight.
"It was a dream, he told himself firmly. "
I dreamed a giant called Hagrid came to
tell me I was going to a school for wizards.
When I open my eyes I'll
be at home in my cupboard."
There was suddenly a loud tapping noise.
And there's Aunt Petunia knocking on the door,
Harry thought,
his heart sinking.
But he still didn't open his eyes.
It had been such a good dream.
Tap. Tap. Tap.
"All right,"
Harry mumbled,
"I'm getting up."
He sat up and Hagrid's heavy coat fell off him.
The hut was full of sunlight,
the storm was over,
Hagrid himself was asleep on the collapsed sofa,
and there was an owl rapping
its claw on the window,
a newspaper held in its beak.
Harry scrambled to his feet,
so happy he felt as though a large
balloon was swelling inside him.
He went straight to the window and jerked it open.
The owl swooped in and dropped
the newspaper on top of Hagrid,
who didn't wake up.
The owl then fluttered onto the floor
and began to attack Hagrid's coat.
"Don't do that."
Harry tried to wave the owl out of the way,
but it snapped its beak fiercely at
him and carried on savaging the coat.
"Hagrid!"
said Harry loudly. "There's an owl
"Pay him,"
Hagrid grunted into the sofa.
"What?"
"He wants payin' fer deliverin'
the paper. Look in the pockets."
Hagrid's coat seemed to be
made of nothing but pockets ,
bunches of keys,
slug pellets,
balls of string,
peppermint humbugs, teabags...
finally, Harry pulled out a
handful of strange-looking coins.
"Give him five Knuts,"
said Hagrid sleepily.
"Knuts?"
"The little bronze ones."
Harry counted out five little bronze coins,
and the owl held out his leg so Harry could put
the money into a small leather pouch tied to it.
Then he flew off through the open window.
Hagrid yawned loudly, sat up, and stretched.
"Best be Off,
Harry, lots ter do today,
gotta get up ter London an'
buy all yer stuff fer school."
Harry was turning over the
wizard coins and looking at them.
He had just thought of something
that made him feel as though the happy
balloon inside him had got a puncture.
"Um , Hagrid?"
"Mm?"
said Hagrid, who was pulling on his huge boots.
"I haven't got any money ,
and you heard Uncle Vernon last night ...
he won't pay for me to go and learn magic."
"Don't worry about that,"
said Hagrid, standing up and scratching his head.
"D'yeh think yer parents
didn't leave yeh anything?"
"But if their house was destroyed , "
"They didn' keep their gold in the house, boy!
Nah, first stop fer us is Gringotts.
Wizards' bank.
Have a sausage,
they're not bad cold ,
an' I wouldn' say no teh a
bit o' yer birthday cake,
neither."
"Wizards have banks?"
"Just the one. Gringotts. Run by goblins."
Harry dropped the bit of sausage he was holding.
"Goblins?"
"Yeah , so yeh'd be mad ter try an' rob it,
I'll tell yeh that.
Never mess with goblins, Harry.
Gringotts is the safest place in the world
fer anything yeh want ter keep safe ,
'cept maybe Hogwarts.
As a matter o' fact,
I gotta visit Gringotts anyway.
Fer Dumbledore.
Hogwarts business."
Hagrid drew himself up proudly.
"He usually gets me ter do
important stuff fer him.
Fetchin' you gettin' things from Gringotts ,
knows he can trust me, see.
"Got everythin'? Come on, then."
Harry followed Hagrid out onto the rock.
The sky was quite clear now and
the sea gleamed in the sunlight.
The boat Uncle Vernon had hired was still there,
with a lot of water in the bottom after the storm.
"How did you get here?"
Harry asked, looking around for another boat.
"Flew,"
said Hagrid.
"Flew?"
"Yeah , but we'll go back in this.
Not s'pposed ter use magic now I've got yeh."
They settled down in the boat,
Harry still staring at Hagrid,
trying to imagine him flying.
"Seems a shame ter row, though,"
said Hagrid, giving Harry
another of his sideways looks.
"If I was ter ,
er , speed things up a bit,
would yeh mind not mentionin' it at Hogwarts?"
"Of course not,"
said Harry,
eager to see more magic.
Hagrid pulled out the pink umbrella again,
tapped it twice on the side of the boat,
and they sped off toward land.
"Why would you be mad to try and rob Gringotts?"
Harry asked.
"Spells , enchantments,"
said Hagrid, unfolding his newspaper as he spoke.
"They say there's dragons
guardin' the highsecurity vaults.
And then yeh gotta find yer way ,
Gringotts is hundreds of miles under London, see.
Deep under the Underground.
Yeh'd die of hunger tryin' ter get out,
even if yeh did manage ter
get yer hands on summat."
Harry sat and thought about this
while Hagrid read his newspaper,
the Daily Prophet.
Harry had learned from Uncle Vernon
that people liked to be left alone while
they did this,
but it was very difficult,
he'd never had so many questions in his life.
"Ministry o' Magic messin' things up as usual,"
Hagrid muttered, turning the page.
"There's a Ministry of Magic?"
Harry asked, before he could stop himself.
"'Course,"
said Hagrid.
"They wanted Dumbledore fer Minister,
0 ' course,
but he'd never leave Hogwarts,
so old Cornelius Fudge got the job.
Bungler if ever there was one.
So he pelts Dumbledore with owls every morning,
askin' fer advice."
"But what does a Ministry of Magic do?"
"Well, their main job is
to keep it from the Muggles
that there's still witches an'
wizards up an' down the country."
"Why?" "Why?
Blimey, Harry,
everyone'd be wantin' magic
solutions to their problems.
Nah, we're best left alone."
At this moment the boat bumped
gently into the harbor wall.
Hagrid folded up his newspaper,
and they clambered up the
stone steps onto the street.
Passersby stared a lot at Hagrid as they
walked through the little town to the station.
Harry couldn't blame them.
Not only was Hagrid twice as tall as anyone else,
he kept pointing at perfectly ordinary
things like parking meters and saying loudly,
"See that, Harry? Things
these Muggles dream up, eh?"
"Hagrid,"
said Harry, panting a bit as he ran to keep up,
"did you say there are dragons at Gringotts?"
"Well, so they say,"
said Hagrid.
"Crikey, I'd like a dragon."
"You'd like one?"
"Wanted one ever since I was a kid , here we go."
They had reached the station.
There was a train to London in five minutes' time.
Hagrid, who didn't understand
"Muggle money,"
as he called it,
gave the bills to Harry so
he could buy their tickets.
People stared more than ever on the train.
Hagrid took up two seats and sat knitting
what looked like a canary-yellow circus tent.
"Still got yer letter, Harry?"
he asked as he counted stitches.
Harry took the parchment
envelope out of his pocket.
"Good,"
said Hagrid.
"There's a list there of everything yeh need."
Harry unfolded a second piece of paper
he hadn't noticed the night before,
and read:
HOGWARTS SCHOOL of WITCHCRAFT and WIZARDRY
UNIFORM
First-year students will require:
1. Three sets of plain work robes (black)
2. One plain pointed hat (black) for day wear
3. One pair of protective
gloves (dragon hide or similar)
4. One winter cloak (black, silver fastenings)
Please note that all pupils'
clothes should carry name tags
COURSE BOOKS
All students should have a
copy of each of the following:
The Standard Book of Spells
(Grade 1) by Miranda Goshawk
A History of Magic by Bathilda Bagshot
Magical Theory by Adalbert Waffling
A Beginners' Guide to
Transfiguration by Emetic Switch
One Thousand Magical Herbs
and Fungi by Phyllida Spore
Magical Drafts and Potions by Arsenius Jigger
Fantastic Beasts and Where to
Find Them by Newt Scamander
The Dark Forces: A Guide to
Self-Protection by Quentin Trimble
OTHER EQUIPMENT
wand cauldron (pewter, standard size 2) set
glass or crystal phials
telescope set
brass scales
Students may also bring an owl OR a cat OR a toad
PARENTS ARE REMINDED THAT FIRST YEARS
ARE NOT ALLOWED THEIR OWN BROOMSTICKS
"Can we buy all this in London?"
Harry wondered aloud.
"If yeh know where to go,"
said Hagrid.
Harry had never been to London before.
Although Hagrid seemed to know where he was going,
he was obviously not used to
getting there in an ordinary way.
He got stuck in the ticket
barrier on the Underground,
and complained loudly that the seats
were too small and the trains too slow.
"I don't know how the Muggles
manage without magic,"
he said as they climbed a broken-down
escalator that led up to a bustling road lined
with shops.
Hagrid was so huge that he
parted the crowd easily;
all Harry had to do was keep close behind him.
They passed book shops and music stores,
hamburger restaurants and cinemas,
but nowhere that looked as if
it could sell you a magic wand.
This was just an ordinary
street full of ordinary people.
Could there really be piles of wizard
gold buried miles beneath them?
Were there really shops that
sold spell books and broomsticks?
Might this not all be some huge joke
that the Dursleys had cooked up?
If Harry hadn't known that the
Dursleys had no sense of humor,
he might have thought so;
yet somehow,
even though everything Hagrid had
told him so far was unbelievable,
Harry couldn't help trusting him.
"This is it,"
said Hagrid, coming to a halt,
"the Leaky Cauldron. It's a famous place."
It was a tiny,
grubby-looking pub.
If Hagrid hadn't pointed it out,
Harry wouldn't have noticed it was there.
The people hurrying by didn't glance at it.
Their eyes slid from the big book shop on
one side to the record shop on the other
as if they couldn't see the Leaky Cauldron at all.
In fact, Harry had the most peculiar feeling
that only he and Hagrid could see it.
Before he could mention this,
Hagrid had steered him inside.
For a famous place,
it was very dark and shabby.
A few old women were sitting in a corner,
drinking tiny glasses of sherry.
One of them was smoking a long pipe.
A little man in a top hat was
talking to the old bartender,
who was quite bald and looked
like a toothless walnut.
The low buzz of chatter
stopped when they walked in.
Everyone seemed to know Hagrid;
they waved and smiled at him,
and the bartender reached for a glass,
saying, "The usual, Hagrid?"
"Can't, Tom, I'm on Hogwarts business,"
said Hagrid,
clapping his great hand on Harry's
shoulder and making Harry's knees buckle.
"Good Lord,"
said the bartender, peering at Harry,
"is this , can this be , ?"
The Leaky Cauldron had suddenly
gone completely still and silent.
"Bless my soul,"
whispered the old bartender,
"Harry Potter... what an honor."
He hurried out from behind the bar,
rushed toward Harry and seized his hand,
tears in his eyes.
"Welcome back, Mr. Potter, welcome back."
Harry didn't know what to say.
Everyone was looking at him.
The old woman with the pipe was puffing
on it without realizing it had gone out.
Hagrid was beaming.
Then there was a great scraping
of chairs and the next moment,
Harry found himself shaking hands
with everyone in the Leaky Cauldron.
"Doris Crockford,
Mr. Potter,
can't believe I'm meeting you at last."
"So proud, Mr. Potter, I'm just so proud."
"Always wanted to shake your
hand , I'm all of a flutter."
"Delighted,
Mr. Potter,
just can't tell you,
Diggle's the name,
Dedalus Diggle."
"I've seen you before!"
said Harry, as Dedalus Diggle's
top hat fell off in his excitement.
"You bowed to me once in a shop."
"He remembers!"
cried Dedalus Diggle, looking around at everyone.
"Did you hear that? He remembers me!"
Harry shook hands again and again ,
Doris Crockford kept coming back for more.
A pale young man made his way forward,
very nervously.
One of his eyes was twitching.
"Professor Quirrell!"
said Hagrid.
"Harry, Professor Quirrell will be
one of your teachers at Hogwarts."
"P-P-Potter,"
stammered Professor Quirrell,
grasping Harry's hand,
"c-can't t-tell you how p-
pleased I am to meet you."
"What sort of magic do you
teach, Professor Quirrell?"
"D-Defense Against the D-D-Dark Arts,"
muttered Professor Quirrell,
as though he'd rather not think about it.
"N-not that you n-need it, eh, P-P-Potter?"
He laughed nervously.
"You'll be g-getting all
your equipment, I suppose?
I've g-got to p-pick up a new b-book on vampires,
m-myself."
He looked terrified at the very thought.
But the others wouldn't let Professor
Quirrell keep Harry to himself.
It took almost ten minutes
to get away from them all.
At last, Hagrid managed to make
himself heard over the babble.
"Must get on , lots ter buy. Come on, Harry."
Doris Crockford shook Harry's hand one last time,
and Hagrid led them through
the bar and out into a small,
walled courtyard,
where there was nothing but
a trash can and a few weeds.
Hagrid grinned at Harry.
"Told yeh, didn't I?
Told yeh you was famous.
Even Professor Quirrell was
tremblin' ter meet yeh ,
mind you, he's usually tremblin'."
"Is he always that nervous?"
"Oh, yeah. Poor bloke. Brilliant
mind. He was fine while he was
studyin' outta books but then he took a year
off ter get some firsthand experience....
They say he met vampires in the Black Forest,
and there was a nasty bit o' trouble with a hag ,
never been the same since.
Scared of the students,
scared of his own subject now,
where's me umbrella?" Vampires? Hags?
Harry's head was swimming.
Hagrid, meanwhile,
was counting bricks in the
wall above the trash can.
"Three up... two across he muttered. "
Right, stand back, Harry."
He tapped the wall three times
with the point of his umbrella.
The brick he had touched quivered ,
it wriggled ,
in the middle,
a small hole appeared ,
it grew wider and wider ,
a second later they were facing an
archway large enough even for Hagrid,
an archway onto a cobbled street
that twisted and turned out of sight.
"Welcome,"
said Hagrid,
"to Diagon Alley."
He grinned at Harry's amazement.
They stepped through the archway.
Harry looked quickly over his shoulder
and saw the archway shrink
instantly back into solid wall.
The sun shone brightly on a stack of
cauldrons outside the nearest shop.
Cauldrons ,
All Sizes - Copper,
Brass, Pewter,
Silver , Self-Stirring ,
Collapsible,
said a sign hanging over them.
"Yeah, you'll be needin' one,"
said Hagrid,
"but we gotta get yer money first."
Harry wished he had about eight more eyes.
He turned his head in every direction
as they walked up the street,
trying to look at everything at once: the shops,
the things outside them,
the people doing their shopping.
A plump woman outside an Apothecary
was shaking her head as they passed,
saying, "Dragon liver, seventeen
Sickles an ounce, they're mad...."
A low, soft hooting came from a dark shop
with a sign saying Eeylops Owl Emporium ,
Tawny, Screech,
Barn, Brown, and Snowy.
Several boys of about Harry's age had
their noses pressed against a window
with broomsticks in it.
"Look,"
Harry heard one of them say,
"the new Nimbus Two Thousand , fastest ever , "
There were shops selling robes,
shops selling telescopes and strange silver
instruments Harry had never seen before,
windows stacked with barrels
of bat spleens and eels' eyes,
tottering piles of spell books,
quills, and rolls of parchment,
potion bottles,
globes of the moon....
"Gringotts,"
said Hagrid.
They had reached a snowy white building
that towered over the other little shops.
Standing beside its burnished bronze doors,
wearing a uniform of scarlet and gold,
was -
"Yeah, that's a goblin,"
said Hagrid quietly as they walked
up the white stone steps toward him.
The goblin was about a head shorter than Harry.
He had a swarthy,
clever face,
a pointed beard and,
Harry noticed,
very long fingers and feet.
He bowed as they walked inside.
Now they were facing a second pair of doors,
silver this time,
with words engraved upon them:
Enter, stranger, but take heed
Of what awaits the sin of greed,
For those who take, but do not earn,
Must pay most dearly in their turn.
So if you seek beneath our floors
A treasure that was never yours,
Thief, you have been warned, beware
Of finding more than treasure there.
"Like I said, Yeh'd be mad ter try an' rob it,"
said Hagrid.
A pair of goblins bowed them through the silver
doors and they were in a vast marble hall.
About a hundred more goblins were sitting
on high stools behind a long counter,
scribbling in large ledgers,
weighing coins in brass scales,
examining precious stones through eyeglasses.
There were too many doors to
count leading off the hall,
and yet more goblins were showing
people in and out of these.
Hagrid and Harry made for the counter.
"Morning,"
said Hagrid to a free goblin.
"We've come ter take some money
outta Mr. Harry Potter's safe."
"You have his key, Sir?"
"Got it here somewhere,"
said Hagrid,
and he started emptying his
pockets onto the counter,
scattering a handful of moldy dog biscuits
over the goblin's book of numbers.
The goblin wrinkled his nose.
Harry watched the goblin on their right weighing
a pile of rubies as big as glowing coals.
"Got it,"
said Hagrid at last, holding up a tiny golden key.
The goblin looked at it closely.
"That seems to be in order."
"An' I've also got a letter
here from Professor Dumbledore,"
said Hagrid importantly, throwing out his chest.
"It's about the YouKnow-What in
vault seven hundred and thirteen."
The goblin read the letter carefully.
"Very well,"
he said, handing it back to Hagrid,
"I will have Someone take you
down to both vaults. Griphook!"
Griphook was yet another goblin.
Once Hagrid had crammed all the dog
biscuits back inside his pockets,
he and Harry followed Griphook toward
one of the doors leading off the hall.
"What's the You-Know-What in
vault seven hundred and thirteen?"
Harry asked.
"Can't tell yeh that,"
said Hagrid mysteriously.
"Very secret.
Hogwarts business.
Dumbledore's trusted me.
More'n my job's worth ter tell yeh that."
Griphook held the door open for them.
Harry, who had expected more marble,
was surprised.
They were in a narrow stone
passageway lit with flaming torches.
It sloped steeply downward and there
were little railway tracks on the floor.
Griphook whistled and a small cart came
hurtling up the tracks toward them.
They climbed in ,
Hagrid with some difficulty ,
and were off.
At first they just hurtled through
a maze of twisting passages.
Harry tried to remember,
left, right,
right, left,
middle fork,
but it was impossible.
The rattling cart seemed to know its own way,
because Griphook wasn't steering.
Harry's eyes stung as the
cold air rushed past them,
but he kept them wide open.
Once, he thought he saw a burst of fire at
the end of a passage and twisted around to see
if it was a dragon,
but too late - - they plunged even deeper,
passing an underground lake
where huge stalactites and stalagmites
grew from the ceiling and floor.
I never know,
" Harry called to Hagrid
over the noise of the cart, "
what's the difference between
a stalagmite and a stalactite?"
"Stalagmite's got an 'm' in it,"
said Hagrid.
"An' don' ask me questions just
now, I think I'm gonna be sick."
He did look very green,
and when the cart stopped at last
beside a small door in the passage wall,
Hagrid got out and had to lean against
the wall to stop his knees from trembling.
Griphook unlocked the door.
A lot of green smoke came billowing out,
and as it cleared,
Harry gasped.
Inside were mounds of gold coins.
Columns of silver.
Heaps of little bronze Knuts.
"All yours,"
smiled Hagrid.
All Harry's ,
it was incredible.
The Dursleys couldn't have known about this
or they'd have had it from
him faster than blinking.
How often had they complained
how much Harry cost them to keep?
And all the time there had been
a small fortune belonging to him,
buried deep under London.
Hagrid helped Harry pile some of it into a bag.
"The gold ones are Galleons,"
he explained.
"Seventeen silver Sickles to a Galleon
and twenty-nine Knuts to a Sickle,
it's easy enough.
Right, that should be enough
fer a couple o' terms,
we'll keep the rest safe for yeh."
He turned to Griphook.
"Vault seven hundred and thirteen now,
please, and can we go more slowly?"
"One speed only,"
said Griphook.
They were going even deeper
now and gathering speed.
The air became colder and colder as
they hurtled round tight corners.
They went rattling over an underground ravine,
and Harry leaned over the side to try
to see what was down at the dark bottom,
but Hagrid groaned and pulled him
back by the scruff of his neck.
Vault seven hundred and thirteen had no keyhole.
"Stand back,"
said Griphook importantly.
He stroked the door gently with one of his
long fingers and it simply melted away.
"If anyone but a Gringotts goblin tried that,
they'd be sucked through the
door and trapped in there,"
said Griphook.
"How often do you check to
see if anyone's inside?"
Harry asked.
"About once every ten years,"
said Griphook with a rather nasty grin.
Something really extraordinary had
to be inside this top security vault,
Harry was sure,
and he leaned forward eagerly,
expecting to see fabulous
jewels at the very least ,
but at first he thought it was empty.
Then he noticed a grubby little package
wrapped up in brown paper lying on the floor.
Hagrid picked it up and tucked
it deep inside his coat.
Harry longed to know what it was,
but knew better than to ask.
"Come on, back in this infernal cart,
and don't talk to me on the way back,
it's best if I keep me mouth shut,"
said Hagrid.
One wild cart ride later they stood
blinking in the sunlight outside Gringotts.
Harry didn't know where to run first
now that he had a bag full of money.
He didn't have to know
how many Galleons there were to a pound to know
that he was holding more money than he'd had
in his whole life ,
more money than even Dudley had ever had.
"Might as well get yer uniform,"
said Hagrid, nodding toward Madam
Malkin's Robes for All Occasions.
"Listen, Harry,
would yeh mind if I slipped off fer
a pick-me-up in the Leaky Cauldron?
I hate them Gringotts carts."
He did still look a bit sick,
so Harry entered Madam Malkin's shop alone,
feeling nervous.
Madam Malkin was a squat, smiling
witch dressed all in mauve.
"Hogwarts, clear?"
she said, when Harry started to speak.
"Got the lot here ,
another young man being
fitted up just now, in fact.
"
In the back of the shop,
a boy with a pale,
pointed face was standing
on a footstool while a second witch
pinned up his long black robes.
Madam Malkin stood Harry on a stool next
to him) slipped a long robe over his head,
and began to pin it to the right length.
"Hello,"
said the boy,
"Hogwarts, too?"
"Yes,"
said Harry.
"My father's next door buying my books and
mother's up the street looking at wands,"
said the boy. He had a bored, drawling voice.
"Then I'm going to drag them
off to took at racing brooms.
I don't see why first years can't have their own.
I think I'll bully father into getting
me one and I'll smuggle it in somehow."
Harry was strongly reminded of Dudley.
"Have you got your own broom?"
the boy went on.
"No,"
said Harry.
"Play Quidditch at all?"
"No,"
Harry said again, wondering what
on earth Quidditch could be.
"I do , Father says it's a crime if
I'm not picked to play for my house,
and I must say, I agree.
Know what house you'll be in yet?"
"No,"
said Harry, feeling more stupid by the minute.
"Well, no one really knows until they get there,
do they, but I know I'll be in Slytherin,
all our family have been ,
imagine being in Hufflepuff,
I think I'd leave,
wouldn't you?"
"Mmm,"
said Harry, wishing he could say
something a bit more interesting.
"I say, look at that man!"
said the boy suddenly,
nodding toward the front window.
Hagrid was standing there,
grinning at Harry and pointing at two large
ice creams to show he couldn't come in.
"That's Hagrid,"
said Harry, pleased to know
something the boy didn't.
"He works at Hogwarts."
"Oh,"
said the boy,
"I've heard of him. He's a
sort of servant, isn't he?"
"He's the gamekeeper,"
said Harry. He was liking the
boy less and less every second.
"Yes, exactly.
I heard he's a sort of savage ,
lives in a hut on the school grounds
and every now and then he gets drunk,
tries to do magic,
and ends up setting fire to his bed."
"I think he's brilliant,"
said Harry coldly.
"Do you?"
said the boy, with a slight sneer.
"Why is he with you? Where are your parents?"
"They're dead,"
said Harry shortly.
He didn't feel much like going
into the matter with this boy.
"Oh, sorry,"
said the other,. not sounding sorry at all.
"But they were our kind, weren't they?"
"They were a witch and wizard,
if that's what you mean."
"I really don't think they should
let the other sort in, do you?
They're just not the same,
they've never been brought up to know our ways.
Some of them have never even heard of
Hogwarts until they get the letter, imagine.
I think they should keep it
in the old wizarding families.
What's your surname,
anyway?"
But before Harry could answer, Madam Malkin said,
"That's you done, my dear,"
and Harry, not sorry for an
excuse to stop talking to the boy,
hopped down from the footstool.
"Well, I'll see you at Hogwarts, I suppose,"
said the drawling boy.
Harry was rather quiet as he ate the ice
cream Hagrid had bought him (chocolate
and raspberry with chopped nuts).
"What's up?"
said Hagrid.
"Nothing,"
Harry lied.
They stopped to buy parchment and quills.
Harry cheered up a bit when he found a bottle
of ink that changed color as you wrote.
When they had left the shop,
he said, "Hagrid, what's Quidditch?"
"Blimey, Harry,
I keep forgettin' how little yeh know ,
not knowin' about Quidditch!"
"Don't make me feel worse,"
said Harry. He told Hagrid about
the pate boy in Madam Malkin's.
", and he said people from Muggle
families shouldn't even be allowed in."
"Yer not from a Muggle family.
If he'd known who yeh were ,
he's grown up knowin' yer name if
his parents are wizardin' folk.
You saw what everyone in the Leaky
Cauldron was like when they saw yeh.
Anyway, what does he know about it,
some o' the best I ever saw
were the only ones with magic
in 'em in a long line 0' Muggles ,
look at yer mum!
Look what she had fer a sister!"
"So what is Quidditch?"
"It's our sport.
Wizard sport.
It's like ,
like soccer in the Muggle world ,
everyone follows Quidditch ,
played up in the air on broomsticks
and there's four balls ,
sorta hard ter explain the rules."
"And what are Slytherin and Hufflepuff?"
"School houses.
There's four.
Everyone says Hufflepuff are a lot o' duffers,
but , "
"I bet I'm in Hufflepuff"
said Harry gloomily.
"Better Hufflepuff than Slytherin,"
said Hagrid darkly.
"There's not a single witch or wizard
who went bad who wasn't in Slytherin.
You-Know-Who was one."
"Vol-, sorry - You-Know-Who was at Hogwarts?"
"Years an' years ago,"
said Hagrid.
They bought Harry's school books in
a shop called Flourish and Blotts
where the shelves were stacked to the ceiling
with books as large as paving stones bound
in leather;
books the size of postage
stamps in covers of silk;
books full of peculiar symbols and a
few books with nothing in them at all.
Even Dudley,
who never read anything,
would have been wild to get
his hands on some of these.
Hagrid almost had to drag Harry away from Curses
and Countercurses (Bewitch Your Friends
and Befuddle Your Enemies with
the Latest Revenges: Hair Loss,
Jelly-Legs,
Tongue- Tying and Much,
Much More) by Professor Vindictus Viridian.
"I was trying to find out how to curse Dudley."
"I'm not sayin' that's not a good idea,
but yer not ter use magic in the Muggle
world except in very special circumstances,"
said Hagrid.
"An' anyway,
yeh couldn' work any of them curses yet,
yeh'll need a lot more study
before yeh get ter that level."
Hagrid wouldn't let Harry buy
a solid gold cauldron, either (
"It says pewter on yer list"
), but they got a nice set of scales
for weighing potion ingredients
and a collapsible brass telescope.
Then they visited the Apothecary,
which was fascinating enough to
make up for its horrible smell,
a mixture of bad eggs and rotted cabbages.
Barrels of slimy stuff stood on the floor;
jars of herbs,
dried roots,
and bright powders lined the walls;
bundles of feathers,
strings of fangs,
and snarled claws hung from the ceiling.
While Hagrid asked the man
behind the counter for a supply
of some basic potion ingredients for Harry,
Harry himself examined silver unicorn horns
at twenty-one Galleons each and minuscule,
glittery-black beetle eyes (five Knuts a scoop).
Outside the Apothecary, Hagrid
checked Harry's list again.
"Just yer wand left - A yeah,
an' I still haven't got yeh a birthday present."
Harry felt himself go red.
"You don't have to , "
"I know I don't have to.
Tell yeh what,
I'll get yer animal.
Not a toad,
toads went outta fashion years ago,
yeh'd be laughed at - an' I don' like cats,
they make me sneeze.
I'll get yer an owl.
All the kids want owls,
they're dead useful,
carry yer mail an' everythin'."
Twenty minutes later,
they left Eeylops Owl Emporium,
which had been dark and full
of rustling and flickering,
jewel-bright eyes.
Harry now carried a large cage
that held a beautiful snowy owl,
fast asleep with her head under her wing.
He couldn't stop stammering his thanks,
sounding just like Professor Quirrell.
"Don' mention it,"
said Hagrid gruffly.
"Don' expect you've had a lotta
presents from them Dursleys.
Just Ollivanders left now - only place fer wands,
Ollivanders,
and yeh gotta have the best wand."
A magic wand...
this was what Harry had been
really looking forward to.
The last shop was narrow and shabby.
Peeling gold letters over the door read
Ollivanders: Makers of Fine Wands since 382 B.C.
A single wand lay on a faded
purple cushion in the dusty window.
A tinkling bell rang somewhere in the
depths of the shop as they stepped inside.
It was a tiny place,
empty except for a single,
spindly chair that Hagrid sat on to wait.
Harry felt strangely as though he
had entered a very strict library;
he swallowed a lot of new questions
that had just occurred to him
and looked instead at the thousands of narrow
boxes piled neatly right up to the ceiling.
For some reason,
the back of his neck prickled.
The very dust and silence in here
seemed to tingle with some secret magic.
"Good afternoon,"
said a soft voice.
Harry jumped.
Hagrid must have jumped,
too, because there was a loud crunching noise
and he got quickly off the spindly chair.
An old man was standing before them,
his wide, pale eyes shining like
moons through the gloom of the shop.
"Hello,"
said Harry awkwardly.
"Ah yes,"
said the man.
"Yes, yes. I thought I'd be
seeing you soon. Harry Potter."
It wasn't a question.
"You have your mother's eyes.
It seems only yesterday she was in here herself,
buying her first wand.
Ten and a quarter inches long,
swishy, made of willow.
Nice wand for charm work."
Mr. Ollivander moved closer to Harry.
Harry wished he would blink.
Those silvery eyes were a bit creepy.
"Your father,
on the other hand,
favored a mahogany wand.
Eleven inches. Pliable.
A little more power and
excellent for transfiguration.
Well, I say your father favored it ,
it's really the wand that chooses the wizard,
of course."
Mr. Ollivander had come so close that
he and Harry were almost nose to nose.
Harry could see himself
reflected in those misty eyes.
"And that's where..."
Mr. Ollivander touched the lightning
scar on Harry's forehead with a long,
white finger.
"I'm sorry to say I sold the wand that did it,"
he said softly.
"Thirteen-and-a-half inches. Yew.
Powerful wand,
very powerful,
and in the wrong hands...
well, if I'd known what that wand was
going out into the world to do...."
He shook his head and then, to Harry's
relief, spotted Hagrid. "Rubeus!
Rubeus Hagrid!
How nice to see you again....
Oak, sixteen inches,
rather bendy,
wasn't it?"
"It was, sir, yes,"
said Hagrid.
"Good wand, that one.
But I suppose they snapped it
in half when you got expelled?"
said Mr. Ollivander, suddenly stern.
"Er , yes, they did, yes,"
said Hagrid, shuffling his feet.
"I've still got the pieces, though,"
he added brightly.
"But you don't use them?"
said Mr. Ollivander sharply.
"Oh, no, sit,"
said Hagrid quickly.
Harry noticed he gripped his pink
umbrella very tightly as he spoke.
"Hmmm,"
said Mr. Ollivander, giving
Hagrid a piercing look.
"Well, now , Mr. Potter. Let me see."
He pulled a long tape measure with
silver markings out of his pocket.
"Which is your wand arm?"
"Er , well, I'm right-handed,"
said Harry.
"Hold out your arm. That's it."
He measured Harry from shoulder to finger,
then wrist to elbow,
shoulder to floor,
knee to armpit and round his head.
As he measured,
he said, "Every Ollivander wand has a
core of a powerful magical substance,
Mr. Potter.
We use unicorn hairs,
phoenix tail feathers,
and the heartstrings of dragons.
No two Ollivander wands are the same,
just as no two unicorns,
dragons, or phoenixes are quite the same.
And of course,
you will never get such good
results with another wizard's wand."
Harry suddenly realized that the tape measure,
which was measuring between his nostrils,
was doing this on its own.
Mr. Ollivander was flitting around the shelves,
taking down boxes.
"That will do,"
he said, and the tape measure
crumpled into a heap on the floor.
"Right then,
Mr. Potter.
Try this one.
Beechwood and dragon heartstring.
Nine inches.
Nice and flexible.
just take it and give it a wave."
Harry took the wand and (feeling
foolish) waved it around a bit,
but Mr. Ollivander snatched it
out of his hand almost at once.
"Maple and phoenix feather. Seven
inches. Quite whippy. Try , "
Harry tried ,
but he had hardly raised the wand when it,
too, was snatched back by Mr. Ollivander.
"No, no -here,
ebony and unicorn hair,
eight and a half inches, springy.
Go on, go on,
try it out."
Harry tried. And tried.
He had no idea what Mr.
Ollivander was waiting for.
The pile of tried wands was mounting
higher and higher on the spindly chair,
but the more wands Mr. Ollivander
pulled from the shelves,
the happier he seemed to become.
"Tricky customer, eh?
Not to worry,
we'll find the perfect match here somewhere ,
I wonder, now - - yes,
why not , unusual combination ,
holly and phoenix feather,
eleven inches,
nice and supple."
Harry took the wand.
He felt a sudden warmth in his fingers.
He raised the wand above his head,
brought it swishing down through the dusty air
and a stream of red and gold sparks
shot from the end like a firework,
throwing dancing spots of light on to the walls.
Hagrid whooped and clapped
and Mr. Ollivander cried,
"Oh, bravo!
Yes, indeed,
oh, very good.
Well, well, well...
how curious...
how very curious...
"
He put Harry's wand back into its
box and wrapped it in brown paper,
still muttering,
"Curious... curious..
"Sorry,"
said Harry,
"but what's curious?"
Mr. Ollivander fixed Harry with his pale stare.
"I remember every wand I've ever sold,
Mr. Potter.
Every single wand.
It so happens that the phoenix
whose tail feather is in your wand,
gave another feather ,
just one other.
It is very curious indeed that you should be
destined for this wand when its brother why,
its brother gave you that scar."
Harry swallowed.
"Yes, thirteen-and-a-half inches. Yew.
Curious indeed how these things happen.
The wand chooses the wizard,
remember....
I think we must expect great things from you,
Mr. Potter....
After all, He- Who-Must-Not-Be-Named
did great things ,
terrible, yes,
but great."
Harry shivered.
He wasn't sure he liked Mr. Ollivander too much.
He paid seven gold Galleons for his wand,
and Mr. Ollivander bowed them from his shop.
The late afternoon sun hung
low in the sky as Harry
and Hagrid made their way back down Diagon Alley,
back through the wall,
back through the Leaky Cauldron, now empty.
Harry didn't speak at all as
they walked down the road;
he didn't even notice how much people
were gawking at them on the Underground,
laden as they were with all
their funny-shaped packages,
with the snowy owl asleep
in its cage on Harry's lap.
Up another escalator,
out into Paddington station;
Harry only realized where they were
when Hagrid tapped him on the shoulder.
"Got time fer a bite to eat
before yer train leaves," he said.
He bought Harry a hamburger and they
sat down on plastic seats to eat them.
Harry kept looking around.
Everything looked so strange, somehow.
"You all right, Harry? Yer very quiet,"
said Hagrid.
Harry wasn't sure he could explain.
He'd just had the best birthday of his life ,
and yet , he chewed his hamburger,
trying to find the words.
"Everyone thinks I'm special,"
he said at last.
"All those people in the Leaky Cauldron,
Professor Quirrell,
Mr. Ollivander...
but I don't know anything about magic at all.
How can they expect great things?
I'm famous and I can't even
remember what I'm famous for.
I don't know what happened when Vol-,
sorry , I mean,
the night my parents died."
Hagrid leaned across the table.
Behind the wild beard and eyebrows
he wore a very kind smile.
"Don' you worry, Harry.
You'll learn fast enough.
Everyone starts at the beginning at Hogwarts,
you'll be just fine.
just be yerself.
I know it's hard.
Yeh've been singled out,
an' that's always hard.
But yeh'll have a great time at Hogwarts ,
I did , still do,
'smatter of fact."
Hagrid helped Harry on to the train that
would take him back to the Dursleys,
then handed him an envelope.
"Yer ticket fer Hogwarts, " he said.
"First o' September ,
King's Cross ,
it's all on yer ticket.
Any problems with the Dursleys,
send me a letter with yer owl,
she'll know where to find me....
See yeh soon,
Harry."
The train pulled out of the station.
Harry wanted to watch Hagrid
until he was out of sight;
he rose in his seat and pressed
his nose against the window,
but he blinked and Hagrid had gone.
CHAPTER SIX
THE JOURNEY FROM PLATFORM NINE AND THREE-QUARTERS
Harry's last month with the Dursleys wasn't fun.
True, Dudley was now so scared of Harry
he wouldn't stay in the same room,
while Aunt Petunia and Uncle Vernon
didn't shut Harry in his cupboard,
force him to do anything,
or shout at him ,
in fact, they didn't speak to him at all.
Half terrified,
half furious,
they acted as though any chair
with Harry in it were empty.
Although this was an improvement in many ways,
it did become a bit depressing after a while.
Harry kept to his room,
with his new owl for company.
He had decided to call her Hedwig,
a name he had found in A History of Magic.
His school books were very interesting.
He lay on his bed reading late into the night,
Hedwig swooping in and out of
the open window as she pleased.
It was lucky that Aunt Petunia
didn't come in to vacuum anymore,
because Hedwig kept bringing back dead mice.
Every night before he went to sleep,
Harry ticked off another day on the
piece of paper he had pinned to the wall,
counting down to September the first.
On the last day of August he thought
he'd better speak to his aunt
and uncle about getting to King's
Cross station the next day,
so he went down to the living room where
they were watching a quiz show on television.
He cleared his throat to
let them know he was there,
and Dudley screamed and ran from the room.
"Er , Uncle Vernon?"
Uncle Vernon grunted to show he was listening.
"Er , I need to be at King's Cross
tomorrow to , to go to Hogwarts."
Uncle Vernon grunted again.
"Would it be all right if you gave me a lift?"
Grunt. Harry supposed that meant yes.
"Thank you."
He was about to go back upstairs
when Uncle Vernon actually spoke.
"Funny way to get to a wizards' school, the train.
Magic carpets all got punctures,
have they?"
Harry didn't say anything.
"Where is this school, anyway?"
"I don't know,"
said Harry,
realizing this for the first time.
He pulled the ticket Hagrid had
given him out of his pocket.
"I just take the train from platform nine and
three-quarters at eleven o'clock," he read.
His aunt and uncle stared.
"Platform what?"
"Nine and three-quarters."
"Don't talk rubbish,"
said Uncle Vernon.
"There is no platform nine and three-quarters."
"It's on my ticket."
"Barking,"
said Uncle Vernon,
"howling mad,
the lot of them.
You'll see.
You just wait.
All right, we'll take you to King's Cross.
We're going up to London tomorrow anyway,
or I wouldn't bother."
"Why are you going to London?"
Harry asked, trying to keep things friendly.
"Taking Dudley to the hospital,"
growled Uncle Vernon.
"Got to have that ruddy tail removed
before he goes to Smeltings."
Harry woke at five o'clock the next morning
and was too excited and
nervous to go back to sleep.
He got up and pulled on his jeans
because he didn't want to walk into
the station in his wizard's robes ,
he'd change on the train.
He checked his Hogwarts list yet again
to make sure he had everything he needed,
saw that Hedwig was shut safely in her cage,
and then paced the room,
waiting for the Dursleys to get up.
Two hours later,
Harry's huge,
heavy trunk had been loaded
into the Dursleys' car,
Aunt Petunia had talked Dudley
into sitting next to Harry,
and they had set off.
They reached King's Cross at half past ten.
Uncle Vernon dumped Harry's trunk onto a
cart and wheeled it into the station for him.
Harry thought this was strangely
kind until Uncle Vernon stopped dead,
facing the platforms with
a nasty grin on his face.
"Well, there you are, boy.
Platform nine ,
platform ten.
Your platform should be somewhere in the middle,
but they don't seem to have built it yet,
do they?"
He was quite right, of course.
There was a big plastic
number nine over one platform
and a big plastic number
ten over the one next to it,
and in the middle,
nothing at all.
"Have a good term,"
said Uncle Vernon with an even nastier smile.
He left without another word.
Harry turned and saw the Dursleys drive away.
All three of them were laughing.
Harry's mouth went rather dry.
What on earth was he going to do?
He was starting to attract a lot of funny looks,
because of Hedwig.
He'd have to ask someone.
He stopped a passing guard,
but didn't dare mention platform
nine and three-quarters.
The guard had never heard of Hogwarts and
when Harry couldn't even tell him
what part of the country it was in,
he started to get annoyed,
as though Harry was being stupid on purpose.
Getting desperate,
Harry asked for the train
that left at eleven o'clock,
but the guard said there wasn't one.
In the end the guard strode away,
muttering about time wasters.
Harry was now trying hard not to panic.
According to the large clock
over the arrivals board,
he had ten minutes left to get on the train
to Hogwarts and he had no idea how to do it;
he was stranded in the middle of a
station with a trunk he could hardly lift,
a pocket full of wizard money,
and a large owl.
Hagrid must have forgotten to
tell him something you had to do,
like tapping the third brick on
the left to get into Diagon Alley.
He wondered if he should get out his wand
and start tapping the ticket inspector's
stand between platforms nine and ten.
At that moment a group of people passed
just behind him and he caught a few words of
what they were saying.
", packed with Muggles, of course , "
Harry swung round.
The speaker was a plump woman
who was talking to four boys,
all with flaming red hair.
Each of them was pushing a trunk
like Harry's in front of him ,
and they had an owl.
Heart hammering,
Harry pushed his cart after them.
They stopped and so did he,
just near enough to hear what they were saying.
"Now, what's the platform number?"
said the boys' mother.
"Nine and three-quarters!"
piped a small girl, also red-headed,
who was holding her hand,
"Mom, can't I go... "
"You're not old enough,
Ginny, now be quiet.
All right, Percy,
you go first."
What looked like the oldest boy
marched toward platforms nine and ten.
Harry watched,
careful not to blink in case he missed it ,
but just as the boy reached the dividing
barrier between the two platforms,
a large crowd of tourists
came swarming in front of him
and by the time the last
backpack had cleared away,
the boy had vanished.
"Fred, you next,"
the plump woman said.
"I'm not Fred, I'm George,"
said the boy.
"Honestly, woman,
you call yourself our mother?
CarA you tell I'm George?"
"Sorry, George, dear."
"Only joking, I am Fred,"
said the boy,
and off he went.
His twin called after him to hurry up,
and he must have done so,
because a second later,
he had gone ,
but how had he done it?
Now the third brother was walking briskly
toward the barrier he was almost there ,
and then, quite suddenly,
he wasn't anywhere.
There was nothing else for it.
"Excuse me,"
Harry said to the plump woman.
"Hello, dear," she said.
"First time at Hogwarts? Ron's new, too."
She pointed at the last and youngest of her sons.
He was tall,
thin, and gangling,
with freckles,
big hands and feet,
and a long nose.
"Yes,"
said Harry.
"The thing is , the thing
is, I don't know how to , "
"How to get onto the platform?"
she said kindly, and Harry nodded.
"Not to worry," she said.
"All you have to do is walk straight at
the barrier between platforms nine and ten.
Don't stop and don't be
scared you'll crash into it,
that's very important.
Best do it at a bit of a run if you're nervous.
Go on, go now before Ron."
"Er , okay,"
said Harry.
He pushed his trolley around
and stared at the barrier.
It looked very solid.
He started to walk toward it.
People jostled him on their
way to platforms nine and ten.
Harry walked more quickly.
He was going to smash right into that
barrier and then he'd be in trouble ,
leaning forward on his cart,
he broke into a heavy run ,
the barrier was coming nearer and nearer ,
he wouldn't be able to stop ,
the cart was out of control ,
he was a foot away ,
he closed his eyes ready for the crash ,
It didn't come...
he kept on running...
he opened his eyes.
A scarlet steam engine was waiting
next to a platform packed with people.
A sign overhead said Hogwarts Express,
eleven O'clock.
Harry looked behind him and saw a wrought-iron
archway where the barrier had been,
with the words Platform Nine
and Three-Quarters on it,
He had done it.
Smoke from the engine drifted over
the heads of the chattering crowd,
while cats of every color wound
here and there between their legs.
Owls hooted to one another in a
disgruntled sort of way over the babble
and the scraping of heavy trunks.
The first few carriages were
already packed with students,
some hanging out of the window
to talk to their families,
some fighting over seats.
Harry pushed his cart off down the
platform in search of an empty seat.
He passed a round-faced boy who was saying,
"Gran, I've lost my toad again."
"Oh, Neville,"
he heard the old woman sigh.
A boy with dreadlocks was
surrounded by a small crowd.
"Give us a look, Lee, go on."
The boy lifted the lid of a box in his arms,
and the people around him shrieked and yelled
as something inside poked out a long, hairy leg.
Harry pressed on through the crowd until
he found an empty compartment near the end
of the train.
He put Hedwig inside first
and then started to shove and heave
his trunk toward the train door.
He tried to lift it up the steps
but could hardly raise one end
and twice he dropped it painfully on his foot.
"Want a hand?"
It was one of the red-haired twins
he'd followed through the barrier.
"Yes, please,"
Harry panted.
"Oy, Fred! C'mere and help!"
With the twins' help,
Harry's trunk was at last tucked
away in a corner of the compartment.
"Thanks,"
said Harry, pushing his
sweaty hair out of his eyes.
"What's that?"
said one of the twins suddenly,
pointing at Harry's lightning scar.
"Blimey,"
said the other twin. "Are you
"He is,"
said the first twin.
"Aren't you?"
he added to Harry.
"What?"
said Harry.
"Harry Potter, "
chorused the twins.
"Oh, him,"
said Harry.
"I mean, yes, I am."
The two boys gawked at him,
and Harry felt himself turning red.
Then, to his relief,
a voice came floating in
through the train's open door.
"Fred? George? Are you there?"
"Coming, Mom."
With a last look at Harry, the
twins hopped off the train.
Harry sat down next to the window where,
half hidden,
he could watch the red-haired family on the
platform and hear what they were saying.
Their mother had just taken out her handkerchief.
"Ron, you've got something on your nose."
The youngest boy tried to jerk out of the way,
but she grabbed him and began
rubbing the end of his nose.
"Mom , geroff"
He wriggled free.
"Aaah, has ickle Ronnie
got somefink on his nosie?"
said one of the twins.
"Shut up," said Ron.
"Where's Percy?"
said their mother.
"He's coming now."
The oldest boy came striding into sight.
He had already changed into his
billowing black Hogwarts robes,
and Harry noticed a shiny silver badge
on his chest with the letter P on it.
"Can't stay long, Mother," he said.
"I'm up front,
the prefects have got two
compartments to themselves ,
"
"Oh, are you a prefect, Percy?"
said one of the twins, with
an air of great surprise.
"You should have said something, we had no idea."
"Hang on, I think I remember
him saying something about it,"
said the other twin.
"Once , "
"Or twice , "
"A minute , "
"All summer , "
"Oh, shut up,"
said Percy the Prefect.
"How come Percy gets new robes, anyway?"
said one of the twins.
"Because he's a prefect,"
said their mother fondly.
"All right,
dear, well,
have a good term ,
send me an owl when you get there."
She kissed Percy on the cheek and he left.
Then she turned to the twins.
"Now, you two ,
this year, you behave yourselves.
If I get one more owl telling me you've ,
you've blown up a toilet or ,
"
"Blown up a toilet? We've
never blown up a toilet."
"Great idea though, thanks, Mom."
"It's not funny. And look after Ron."
"Don't worry, ickle Ronniekins is safe with us."
"Shut up,"
said Ron again.
He was almost as tall as the twins
already and his nose was still pink
where his mother had rubbed it.
"Hey, Mom, guess what? Guess
who we just met on the train?"
Harry leaned back quickly so
they couldn't see him looking.
"You know that black-haired boy
who was near us in the station?
Know who he is?"
"Who?"
"Harry Potter!"
Harry heard the little girl's voice.
"Oh, Mom, can I go on the train
and see him, Mom, eh please...."
"You've already seen him,
Ginny, and the poor boy isn't
something you goggle at in a zoo.
Is he really, Fred?
How do you know?"
"Asked him. Saw his scar. It's
really there - like lightning."
"Poor dear - no wonder he was alone,
I wondered.
He was ever so polite when he asked
how to get onto the platform."
"Never mind that,
do you think he remembers
what You-Know-Who looks like?"
Their mother suddenly became very stern.
"I forbid you to ask him, Fred.
No, don't you dare.
As though he needs reminding of
that on his first day at school."
"All right, keep your hair on."
A whistle sounded.
"Hurry up!"
their mother said,
and the three boys clambered onto the train.
They leaned out of the window
for her to kiss them good-bye,
and their younger sister began to cry.
"Don't, Ginny, we'll send you loads of owls."
"We'll send you a Hogwarts toilet seat."
"George!"
"Only joking, Mom."
The train began to move.
Harry saw the boys' mother
waving and their sister,
half laughing,
half crying,
running to keep up with the train
until it gathered too much speed,
then she fell back and waved.
Harry watched the girl and her mother
disappear as the train rounded the corner.
Houses flashed past the window.
Harry felt a great leap of excitement.
He didn't know what he was going
to but it had to be better than
what he was leaving behind.
The door of the compartment slid open
and the youngest redheaded boy came in.
"Anyone sitting there?"
he asked, pointing at the seat opposite Harry.
"Everywhere else is full."
Harry shook his head and the boy sat down.
He glanced at Harry and then
looked quickly out of the window,
pretending he hadn't looked.
Harry saw he still had a black mark on his nose.
"Hey, Ron."
The twins were back.
"Listen, we're going down
the middle of the train ,
Lee Jordan's got a giant tarantula down there."
"Right,"
mumbled Ron.
"Harry,"
said the other twin,
"did we introduce ourselves?
Fred and George Weasley.
And this is Ron,
our brother.
See you later, then.
"Bye,"
said Harry and Ron.
The twins slid the compartment
door shut behind them.
"Are you really Harry Potter?"
Ron blurted out.
Harry nodded.
"Oh -well, I thought it might be one
of Fred and George's jokes," said Ron.
"And have you really got , you know..."
He pointed at Harry's forehead.
Harry pulled back his bangs to show
the lightning scar. Ron stared.
"So that's where You-Know-Who
"Yes,"
said Harry,
"but I can't remember it."
"Nothing?"
said Ron eagerly.
"Well , I remember a lot of
green light, but nothing else."
"Wow," said Ron.
He sat and stared at Harry for a few moments,
then, as though he had suddenly
realized what he was doing,
he looked quickly out of the window again.
"Are all your family wizards?"
asked Harry, who found Ron just
as interesting as Ron found him.
"Er , Yes, I think so," said Ron.
"I think Mom's got a second
cousin who's an accountant,
but we never talk about him."
"So you must know loads of magic already."
The Weasleys were clearly one of those
old wizarding families the pale boy
in Diagon Alley had talked about.
"I heard you went to live with Muggles," said Ron.
"What are they like?"
"Horrible -well,
not all of them.
My aunt and uncle and cousin are, though.
Wish I'd had three wizard brothers."
"Five,"
said Ron. For some reason, he was looking gloomy.
"I'm the sixth in our family to go to Hogwarts.
You could say I've got a lot to live up to.
Bill and Charlie have already left ,
Bill was head boy and Charlie
was captain of Quidditch.
Now Percy's a prefect.
Fred and George mess around a lot,
but they still get really good marks and
everyone thinks they're really funny.
Everyone expects me to do as well as the others,
but if I do,
it's no big deal,
because they did it first.
You never get anything new,
either, with five brothers.
I've got Bill's old robes,
Charlie's old wand,
and Percy's old rat."
Ron reached inside his jacket
and pulled out a fat gray rat,
which was asleep.
"His name's Scabbers and he's useless,
he hardly ever wakes up.
Percy got an owl from my dad
for being made a prefect,
but they couldn't aff ,
I mean, I got Scabbers instead."
Ron's ears went pink.
He seemed to think he'd said too much,
because he went back to staring out of the window.
Harry didn't think there was anything
wrong with not being able to afford an owl.
After all, he'd never had any money
in his life until a month ago,
and he told Ron so,
all about having to wear Dudley's old clothes
and never getting proper birthday presents.
This seemed to cheer Ron up. "...
and until Hagrid told me,
I didn't know anything about be ing a
wizard or about my parents or Voldemort"
Ron gasped.
"What?"
said Harry.
"You said You-Know-Who's name!"
said Ron, sounding both shocked and impressed.
"I'd have thought you, of all people , "
"I'm not trying to be brave
or anything, saying the name,"
said Harry,
I just never knew you shouldn't.
See what I mean?
I've got loads to learn....
I bet, " he added,
voicing for the first time something
that had been worrying him a lot lately,
"
I bet I'm the worst in the class."
"You won't be.
There's loads of people who come from Muggle
families and they learn quick enough."
While they had been talking,
the train had carried them out of London.
Now they were speeding past
fields full of cows and sheep.
They were quiet for a time,
watching the fields and lanes flick past.
Around half past twelve there was a
great clattering outside in the corridor
and a smiling,
dimpled woman slid back their door and said,
"Anything off the cart, dears?"
Harry, who hadn't had any breakfast,
leapt to his feet,
but Ron's ears went pink again and he
muttered that he'd brought sandwiches.
Harry went out into the corridor.
He had never had any money
for candy with the Dursleys,
and now that he had pockets rattling with gold
and silver he was ready to buy as
many Mars Bars as he could carry ,
but the woman didn't have Mars Bars.
What she did have were Bettie
Bott's Every Flavor Beans,
Drooble's Best Blowing Gum,
Chocolate Frogs.
Pumpkin Pasties,
Cauldron Cakes,
Licorice Wands,
and a number of other strange things
Harry had never seen in his life.
Not wanting to miss anything,
he got some of everything and paid the woman
eleven silver Sickles and seven bronze Knuts.
Ron stared as Harry brought it
all back in to the compartment
and tipped it onto an empty seat.
"Hungry, are you?"
"Starving,"
said Harry, taking a large
bite out of a pumpkin pasty.
Ron had taken out a lumpy
package and unwrapped it.
There were four sandwiches inside.
He pulled one of them apart and said,
"She always forgets I don't like corned beef."
"Swap you for one of these,"
said Harry, holding up a pasty.
"Go on , "
"You don't want this, it's all dry," said Ron.
"She hasn't got much time,"
he added quickly,
"you know, with five of us."
"Go on, have a pasty,"
said Harry,
who had never had anything to share before or,
indeed, anyone to share it with.
It was a nice feeling,
sitting there with Ron,
eating their way through all Harry's pasties,
cakes, and candies (the sandwiches lay forgotten).
"What are these?"
Harry asked Ron, holding up
a pack of Chocolate Frogs.
"They're not really frogs, are they?"
He was starting to feel that
nothing would surprise him.
"No," said Ron.
"But see what the card is. I'm missing Agrippa."
"What?"
"Oh, of course,
you wouldn't know ,
Chocolate Frogs have cards,
inside them,
you know, to collect ,
famous witches and wizards.
I've got about five hundred,
but I haven't got Agrippa or Ptolemy."
Harry unwrapped his Chocolate
Frog and picked up the card.
It showed a man's face.
He wore half- moon glasses,
had a long,
crooked nose,
and flowing silver hair,
beard, and mustache.
Underneath the picture was
the name Albus Dumbledore.
"So this is Dumbledore!"
said Harry.
"Don't tell me you'd never heard of Dumbledore!"
said Ron. "Can I have a frog?
I might get Agrippa , thanks
Harry turned over his card and read:
ALBUS DUMBLEDORE
CURRENTLY HEADMASTER OF HOGWARTS
Considered by many the greatest
wizard of modern times,
Dumbledore is particularly famous for his
defeat of the dark wizard Grindelwald in 1945,
for the discovery of the
twelve uses of dragon's blood,
and his work on alchemy with his partner,
Nicolas Flamel.
Professor Dumbledore enjoys
chamber music and tenpin bowling.
Harry turned the card back over and saw,
to his astonishment,
that Dumbledore's face had disappeared.
"He's gone!"
"Well, you can't expect him to
hang around all day," said Ron.
"He'll be back.
No, I've got Morgana again and
I've got about six of her...
do you want it?
You can start collecting."
Ron's eyes strayed to the pile of
Chocolate Frogs waiting to be unwrapped.
"Help yourself,"
said Harry.
"But in, you know, the Muggle world,
people just stay put in photos."
"Do they? What, they don't move at all?"
Ron sounded amazed.
"weird!"
Harry stared as Dumbledore sidled
back into the picture on his card
and gave him a small smile.
Ron was more interested in eating the
frogs than looking at the Famous Witches
and Wizards cards,
but Harry couldn't keep his eyes off them.
Soon he had not only Dumbledore and Morgana,
but Hengist of Woodcroft,
Alberic Grunnion,
Circe, Paracelsus,
and Merlin.
He finally tore his eyes away
from the druidess Cliodna,
who was scratching her nose,
to open a bag of Bertie Bott's Every Flavor Beans.
"You want to be careful with those,"
Ron warned Harry.
"When they say every flavor,
they mean every flavor ,
you know, you get all the ordinary ones like
chocolate and peppermint and mar- malade,
but then you can get spinach and liver and tripe.
George reckons he had a
booger- flavored one once."
Ron picked up a green bean,
looked at it carefully,
and bit into a corner.
"Bleaaargh , see? Sprouts."
They had a good time eating
the Every Flavor Beans.
Harry got toast,
coconut, baked bean,
strawberry,
curry, grass,
coffee, sardine,
and was even brave enough to nibble the end
off a funny gray one Ron wouldn't touch,
which turned out to be pepper.
The countryside now flying past
the window was becoming wilder.
The neat fields had gone.
Now there were woods,
twisting rivers,
and dark green hills.
There was a knock on the door of their compartment
and the round-faced boy Harry had passed
on platform nine and threequarters came in.
He looked tearful.
"Sorry,"
he said, "but have you seen a toad at all?"
When they shook their heads, he wailed,
"I've lost him! He keeps getting away from me!"
"He'll turn up,"
said Harry.
"Yes,"
said the boy miserably.
"Well, if you see him..." He left.
"Don't know why he's so bothered," said Ron.
"If I'd brought a toad I'd
lose it as quick as I could.
Mind you, I brought Scabbers,
so I can't talk."
The rat was still snoozing on Ron's lap.
"He might have died and you
wouldn't know the difference,"
said Ron in disgust.
"I tried to turn him yellow yesterday
to make him more interesting,
but the spell didn't work.
I'll show you,
look..."
He rummaged around in his trunk and
pulled out a very battered-looking wand.
It was chipped in places and something
white was glinting at the end.
"Unicorn hair's nearly poking out. Anyway
He had just raised his 'wand when
the compartment door slid open again.
The toadless boy was back,
but this time he had a girl with him.
She was already wearing her new Hogwarts robes.
"Has anyone seen a toad?
Neville's lost one," she said.
She had a bossy sort of voice,
lots of bushy brown hair,
and rather large front teeth.
"We've already told him we haven't seen it,"
said Ron, but the girl wasn't listening,
she was looking at the wand in his hand.
"Oh, are you doing magic? Let's see it, then."
She sat down. Ron looked taken aback.
"Er , all right."
He cleared his throat.
"Sunshine, daisies, butter mellow,
Turn this stupid, fat rat yellow."
He waved his wand,
but nothing happened.
Scabbers stayed gray and fast asleep.
"Are you sure that's a real spell?"
said the girl.
"Well, it's not very good, is it?
I've tried a few simple spells just for
practice and it's all worked for me.
Nobody in my family's magic at all,
it was ever such a surprise when I got my letter,
but I was ever so pleased,
of course, I mean,
it's the very best school of witchcraft there is,
I've heard ,
I've learned all our course books by heart,
of course, I just hope it will be enough ,
I'm Hermione Granger,
by the way,
who are you.
She said all this very fast.
Harry looked at Ron,
and was relieved to see
by his stunned face that he hadn't learned
all the course books by heart either.
"I'm Ron Weasley,"
Ron muttered.
"Harry Potter,"
said Harry.
"Are you really?"
said Hermione.
"I know all about you,
of course ,
I got a few extra books.
for background reading,
and you're in Modern Magical History
and The Rise and Fall of the Dark Arts
and Great Wizarding Events
of the Twentieth Century.
"Am I?"
said Harry, feeling dazed.
"Goodness, didn't you know,
I'd have found out everything
I could if it was me,"
said Hermione.
"Do either of you know what house you'll be in?
I've been asking around,
and I hope I'm in Gryffindor,
it sounds by far the best;
I hear Dumbledore himself was in it,
but I suppose Ravenclaw wouldn't be too bad....
Anyway, we'd better go and
look for Neville's toad.
You two had better change,
you know, I expect we'll be there soon."
And she left, taking the toadless boy with her.
"Whatever house I'm in, I hope she's not in it,"
said Ron. He threw his wand back into his trunk.
"Stupid spell , George gave it
to me, bet he knew it was a dud."
"What house are your brothers in?"
asked Harry.
"Gryffindor,"
said Ron. Gloom seemed to
be settling on him again.
"Mom and Dad were in it, too.
I don't know what they'll say if I'm not.
I don't suppose Ravenclaw would be too bad,
but imagine if they put me in Slytherin."
"That's the house Vol-, I
mean, You-Know-Who was in?"
"Yeah,"
said Ron. He flopped back into
his seat, looking depressed.
"You know, I think the ends of
Scabbers' whiskers are a bit lighter,"
said Harry, trying to take Ron's mind off houses.
"So what do your oldest brothers
do now that they've left, anyway?"
Harry was wondering what a wizard
did once he'd finished school.
"Charlie's in Romania studying dragons,
and Bill's in Africa doing
something for Gringotts,"
said Ron. "Did you hear about Gringotts?
It's been all over the Daily Prophet,
but I don't suppose you
get that with the Muggles ,
someone tried to rob a high security vault."
Harry stared.
"Really? What happened to them?"
"Nothing, that's why it's such big news.
They haven't been caught.
My dad says it must've been a powerful
Dark wizard to get round Gringotts,
but they don't think they took anything,
that's what's odd.
'Course, everyone gets scared when something like
this happens in case You-Know-Who's behind it."
Harry turned this news over in his mind.
He was starting to get a prickle of fear
every time You- Know-Who was mentioned.
He supposed this was all part
of entering the magical world,
but it had been a lot more comfortable saying
"Voldemort"
without worrying.
"What's your Quidditch team?" Ron asked.
"Er , I don't know any,"
Harry confessed.
"What!"
Ron looked dumbfounded.
"Oh, you wait, it's the best game in the world , "
And he was off,
explaining all about the four balls
and the positions of the seven players,
describing famous games he'd been to with his
brothers and the broomstick he'd like to get
if he had the money.
He was just taking Harry through
the finer points of the game
when the compartment door slid open yet again,
but it wasn't Neville the toadless boy,
or Hermione Granger this time.
Three boys entered,
and Harry recognized the middle one
at once: it was the pale boy
from Madam Malkin's robe shop.
He was looking at Harry with a lot more
interest than he'd shown back in Diagon Alley.
"Is it true?" he said.
"They're saying all down the train that
Harry Potter's in this compartment.
So it's you,
is it?"
"Yes,"
said Harry.
He was looking at the other boys.
Both of them were thickset
and looked extremely mean.
Standing on either side of the pale boy,
they looked like bodyguards.
"Oh, this is Crabbe and this is Goyle,"
said the pale boy carelessly,
noticing where Harry was looking.
"And my name's Malfoy, Draco Malfoy."
Ron gave a slight cough,
which might have been hiding a snigget.
Draco Malfoy looked at him.
"Think my name's funny, do you?
No need to ask who you are.
My father told me all the Weasleys have red hair,
freckles, and more children than they can afford."
He turned back to Harry.
"You'll soon find out some wizarding
families are much better than others, Potter.
You don't want to go making
friends with the wrong sort.
I can help you there."
He held out his hand to shake
Harry's, but Harry didn't take it.
"I think I can tell who the wrong
sort are for myself, thanks,"
he said coolly.
Draco Malfoy didn't go red,
but a pink tinge appeared in his pale cheeks.
"I'd be careful if I were you, Potter,"
he said slowly.
"Unless you're a bit politer you'll
go the same way as your parents.
They didn't know what was good for them, either.
You hang around with riffraff
like the Weasleys and that Hagrid,
and it'll rub off on you."
Both Harry and Ron stood up.
"Say that again,"
Ron said, his face as red as his hair.
"Oh, you're going to fight us, are you?"
Malfoy sneered.
"Unless you get out now,"
said Harry,
more bravely than he felt,
because Crabbe and Goyle were
a lot bigger than him or Ron.
"But we don't feet like leaving,
do we, boys?
We've eaten all our food and
you still seem to have some."
Goyle reached toward the Chocolate
Frogs next to Ron - Ron leapt forward,
but before he'd so much as touched Goyle,
Goyle let out a horrible yell.
Scabbers the rat was hanging off his finger,
sharp little teeth sunk deep
into Goyle's knuckle - Crabbe
and Malfoy backed away as Goyle
swung Scabbers round and round,
howling, and when Scabbets finally
flew off and hit the window,
all three of them disappeared at once.
Perhaps they thought there were
more rats lurking among the sweets,
or perhaps they'd heard footsteps,
because a second later,
Hermione Granger had come in.
"What has been going on?"
she said, looking at the sweets all over the
floor and Ron picking up Scabbers by his tail.
I think he's been knocked out,
" Ron said to Harry. He
looked closer at Scabbers. "
No , I don't believe it ,
he's gone back to sleep-"
And so he had.
"You've met Malfoy before?"
Harry explained about their
meeting in Diagon Alley.
"I've heard of his family,"
said Ron darkly.
"They were some of the first to come back
to our side after You-Know-Who disappeared.
Said they'd been bewitched.
My dad doesn't believe it.
He says Malfoy's father didn't need an
excuse to go over to the Dark Side."
He turned to Hermione.
"Can we help you with something?"
"You'd better hurry up and put your robes on,
I've just been up to the
front to ask the conductor,
and he says we're nearly there.
You haven't been fighting, have you?
You'll be in trouble before we even get there!"
"Scabbers has been fighting, not us,"
said Ron, scowling at her.
"Would you mind leaving while we change?"
"All right ,
I only came in here because people
outside are behaving very childishly,
racing up and down the corridors,"
said Hermione in a sniffy voice.
"And you've got dirt on your
nose, by the way, did you know?"
Ron glared at her as she left.
Harry peered out of the window.
It was getting dark.
He could see mountains and
forests under a deep purple sky.
The train did seem to be slowing down.
He and Ron took off their jackets
and pulled on their long black robes.
Ron's were a bit short for him,
you could see his sneakers underneath them.
A voice echoed through the train:
"We will be reaching Hogwarts
in five minutes' time.
Please leave your luggage on the train,
it will be taken to the school separately."
Harry's stomach lurched with nerves and Ron,
he saw, looked pale under his freckles.
They crammed their pockets
with the last of the sweets
and joined the crowd thronging the corridor.
The train slowed right down and finally stopped.
People pushed their way toward
the door and out on to a tiny,
dark platform.
Harry shivered in the cold night air.
Then a lamp came bobbing over
the heads of the students,
and Harry heard a familiar voice:
"Firs' years! Firs' years over
here! All right there, Harry?"
Hagrid's big hairy face
beamed over the sea of heads.
"C'mon, follow me ,
any more firs' years?
Mind yer step, now!
Firs' years follow me!"
Slipping and stumbling,
they followed Hagrid down
what seemed to be a steep,
narrow path.
It was so dark on either side of them that
Harry thought there must be thick trees there.
Nobody spoke much.
Neville, the boy who kept losing his toad,
sniffed once or twice.
"Ye' all get yer firs'
sight o' Hogwarts in a sec,"
Hagrid called over his shoulder,
"jus' round this bend here."
There was a loud
"Oooooh!"
The narrow path had opened suddenly
onto the edge of a great black take.
Perched atop a high mountain on the other side,
its windows sparkling in the starry sky,
was a vast castle with many turrets and towers.
"No more'n four to a boat!"
Hagrid called,
pointing to a fleet of little boats
sitting in the water by the shore.
Harry and Ron were followed into
their boat by Neville and Hermione.
"Everyone in?"
shouted Hagrid, who had a boat to himself.
"Right then , FORWARD!"
And the fleet of little
boats moved off all at once,
gliding across the lake,
which was as smooth as glass.
Everyone was silent,
staring up at the great castle overhead.
It towered over them as they sailed nearer
and nearer to the cliff on which it stood.
"Heads down!"
yelled Hagrid as the first
boats reached the cliff;
they all bent their heads
and the little boats carried them through
a curtain of ivy that hid a wide opening
in the cliff face.
They were carried along a dark tunnel,
which seemed to be taking them
right underneath the castle,
until they reached a kind of underground harbor,
where they clambered out onto rocks and pebbles.
"Oy, you there! Is this your toad?"
said Hagrid,
who was checking the boats as
people climbed out of them.
"Trevor!"
cried Neville blissfully,
holding out his hands.
Then they clambered up a passageway
in the rock after Hagrid's lamp,
coming out at last onto smooth,
damp grass right in the shadow of the castle.
They walked up a flight of stone
steps and crowded around the huge,
Oak front door.
"Everyone here? You there, still got yer toad?"
Hagrid raised a gigantic fist and
knocked three times on the castle door.